[
  {
    "id": 3501,
    "question": "escuches",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero que me hables o que escuches.",
    "answer": "listen",
    "answerDetails": "I want you to talk or listen."
  },
  {
    "id": 3502,
    "question": "disposición",
    "questionDetails": "Si no estás de acuerdo con esta disposición, no firmes el contrato.",
    "answer": "provision, disposal, disposition",
    "answerDetails": "If you don’t agree with this provision, you shouldn’t sign the contract."
  },
  {
    "id": 3503,
    "question": "servido",
    "questionDetails": "Lo he servido a usted por muchos años.",
    "answer": "served, availed, manned",
    "answerDetails": "I have served you for many years now."
  },
  {
    "id": 3504,
    "question": "alcance",
    "questionDetails": "Ampliamos el alcance de nuestra investigación.",
    "answer": "scope, reach",
    "answerDetails": "We widened the scope of our investigation."
  },
  {
    "id": 3505,
    "question": "suyos",
    "questionDetails": "Y, a cambio, los suyos también sean míos.",
    "answer": "yours",
    "answerDetails": "And in turn, that yours be mine too."
  },
  {
    "id": 3506,
    "question": "llegues",
    "questionDetails": "No llegues muy tarde.",
    "answer": "be",
    "answerDetails": "Try not to be too late."
  },
  {
    "id": 3507,
    "question": "misa",
    "questionDetails": "Todos los domingos, mi abuela va a la iglesia a escuchar misa.",
    "answer": "mass",
    "answerDetails": "Every Sunday, my grandmother goes to church to attend mass."
  },
  {
    "id": 3508,
    "question": "atiende",
    "questionDetails": "Atiende la puerta, como si todo estuviera bien.",
    "answer": "attends, caters, serves",
    "answerDetails": "Attends the door, as if everything was okay."
  },
  {
    "id": 3509,
    "question": "aceptado",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero ser aceptado en la mejor universidad del País.",
    "answer": "accepted",
    "answerDetails": "I want to be accepted at the country’s best university."
  },
  {
    "id": 3510,
    "question": "cojo",
    "questionDetails": "A pesar de su pierna cojo, huyó.",
    "answer": "lame",
    "answerDetails": "Despite his lame leg, he fled."
  },
  {
    "id": 3511,
    "question": "prepara",
    "questionDetails": "Un oficial listo se prepara para una campaña larga.",
    "answer": "prepares, readies, prep",
    "answerDetails": "A smart officer prepares for a long campaign."
  },
  {
    "id": 3512,
    "question": "velocidad",
    "questionDetails": "Brian recibió una bici de 7 velocidades en Navidad.",
    "answer": "speed",
    "answerDetails": "Brian got a 7-speed bike for Christmas."
  },
  {
    "id": 3513,
    "question": "dedica",
    "questionDetails": "Más dedica a su trabajo que a mi.",
    "answer": "dedicated, devoted, engaged",
    "answerDetails": "More dedicated to his job than me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3514,
    "question": "domicilio",
    "questionDetails": "¿Cuál es su domicilio, señor?",
    "answer": "address, domicile, abode",
    "answerDetails": "What is your address, sir?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3515,
    "question": "bolsas",
    "questionDetails": "Esta crema es excelente para camuflar las bolsas bajo los ojos.",
    "answer": "bags",
    "answerDetails": "This cream is great for disguising undereye bags."
  },
  {
    "id": 3516,
    "question": "aventura",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Nuestro viaje de safari en África realmente fue una aventura!.",
    "answer": "adventure, affair, fling",
    "answerDetails": "Our African Safari Trip was a real adventure!."
  },
  {
    "id": 3517,
    "question": "comes",
    "questionDetails": "Eso significa que comes tu propia comida.",
    "answer": "eat",
    "answerDetails": "That means you eat your own food."
  },
  {
    "id": 3518,
    "question": "miente",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo conozco el ruido que hace cuando miente.",
    "answer": "lies",
    "answerDetails": "I just know the sound it makes when it lies."
  },
  {
    "id": 3519,
    "question": "volvería",
    "questionDetails": "Lo volvería a hacer por ti.",
    "answer": "would",
    "answerDetails": "I would do it again for you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3520,
    "question": "pensamiento",
    "questionDetails": "El pensamiento sobre los beneficios del bilingüismo ha evolucionado mucho en los últimos años.",
    "answer": "thinking",
    "answerDetails": "Thinking on the benefits of bilingualism has evolved greatly in recent years."
  },
  {
    "id": 3521,
    "question": "papito",
    "questionDetails": "Debes buscar a mi papito.",
    "answer": "daddy",
    "answerDetails": "You must be looking for my daddy."
  },
  {
    "id": 3522,
    "question": "billete",
    "questionDetails": "Llevaba $100 encima en billetes de uno.",
    "answer": "bill, fare",
    "answerDetails": "He was carrying $100 all in $1 bills."
  },
  {
    "id": 3523,
    "question": "operativo",
    "questionDetails": "El transmisor está operativo.",
    "answer": "operative",
    "answerDetails": "The transmitter is operative."
  },
  {
    "id": 3524,
    "question": "escúcheme",
    "questionDetails": "Escúcheme usted a mí.",
    "answer": "listen",
    "answerDetails": "You listen to me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3525,
    "question": "imagínese",
    "questionDetails": "Imagínese si usted quería poner el jarabe en el agua.",
    "answer": "imagine",
    "answerDetails": "Imagine if you wanted to put syrup in water."
  },
  {
    "id": 3526,
    "question": "frontera",
    "questionDetails": "Laurie se hizo astronauta para tener una carrera en las fronteras del conocimiento humano.",
    "answer": "frontier, boundary",
    "answerDetails": "Laurie became an astronaut so she could have a career at the frontiers of human knowledge."
  },
  {
    "id": 3527,
    "question": "criminal",
    "questionDetails": "Nadie nace siendo un criminal.",
    "answer": "criminal, criminally, felon",
    "answerDetails": "One is not born a criminal."
  },
  {
    "id": 3528,
    "question": "maten",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo que estar allí cuando maten a ese hombre.",
    "answer": "kill, slay, whacked",
    "answerDetails": "I have to be there when they kill this man."
  },
  {
    "id": 3529,
    "question": "traidor",
    "questionDetails": "Esa mujer traidora se me fue y me dejó con el corazón roto.",
    "answer": "treacherous",
    "answerDetails": "That treacherous woman ran away and left me with a broken heart."
  },
  {
    "id": 3530,
    "question": "preocupen",
    "answer": "worry"
  },
  {
    "id": 3531,
    "question": "intereses",
    "questionDetails": "Pablo tiene intereses en varias inmobilarias en la China.",
    "answer": "interests",
    "answerDetails": "Pablo has interests in various construction companies in China."
  },
  {
    "id": 3532,
    "question": "sexual",
    "questionDetails": "La mejor experiencia sexual de mi vida.",
    "answer": "sexual, sexually, sex",
    "answerDetails": "Best sexual experience of my life."
  },
  {
    "id": 3533,
    "question": "regalito",
    "questionDetails": "Ha dicho que tenía un regalito para ti.",
    "answer": "gift",
    "answerDetails": "He said something about a gift for you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3534,
    "question": "evidencia",
    "questionDetails": "Los detectives no encontraron evidencia de que se tratara de un asesinato.",
    "answer": "evidence, proof",
    "answerDetails": "The detectives found no evidence that it was a murder."
  },
  {
    "id": 3535,
    "question": "conveniente",
    "questionDetails": "El sitio tendría que ser conveniente para Londres.",
    "answer": "convenient, suitable, appropriate",
    "answerDetails": "The site would have to be convenient for London."
  },
  {
    "id": 3536,
    "question": "hablen",
    "questionDetails": "Hablen con amigos, compañeros, el repartidor de pizza.",
    "answer": "talk, speak",
    "answerDetails": "Talk to friends, classmates, pizza delivery guy."
  },
  {
    "id": 3537,
    "question": "trató",
    "questionDetails": "Un panorama trató de componer dos piezas de fotografías.",
    "answer": "tried, treated, attempted",
    "answerDetails": "A panorama tried to compose two pieces of photographs."
  },
  {
    "id": 3538,
    "question": "huellas",
    "questionDetails": "Estos son dos juegos nuevos de huellas.",
    "answer": "footprints, prints, fingerprints",
    "answerDetails": "These are two new sets of footprints."
  },
  {
    "id": 3539,
    "question": "levante",
    "answer": "east"
  },
  {
    "id": 3540,
    "question": "bote",
    "questionDetails": "Remaron el bote hacia la orilla, rezando por su supervivencia.",
    "answer": "boat, dinghy, jar",
    "answerDetails": "They rowed the boat toward shore, praying they would survive."
  },
  {
    "id": 3541,
    "question": "hazte",
    "questionDetails": "Hazte fanático del hockey.",
    "answer": "become",
    "answerDetails": "Become a hockey fan."
  },
  {
    "id": 3542,
    "question": "pagarle",
    "questionDetails": "No tengo dinero para pagarle a nadie.",
    "answer": "pay, repay",
    "answerDetails": "I have no money to pay any of you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3543,
    "question": "mírate",
    "questionDetails": "Mírame a mí, y mírate a ti.",
    "answer": "look",
    "answerDetails": "Look at me, and look at you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3544,
    "question": "pidas",
    "answer": "Ask"
  },
  {
    "id": 3545,
    "question": "explique",
    "answer": "Explain"
  },
  {
    "id": 3546,
    "question": "piedras",
    "questionDetails": "Estaban en las piedras.",
    "answer": "stones, rocks, pebbles",
    "answerDetails": "You were at the stones."
  },
  {
    "id": 3547,
    "question": "prefiere",
    "questionDetails": "Su nombre es Micaela, pero prefiere llamarse Mick.",
    "answer": "she prefers",
    "answerDetails": "Her name is Micaela, but she prefers to be called Mick."
  },
  {
    "id": 3548,
    "question": "merecen",
    "questionDetails": "Realmente no merecen manejar la tienda.",
    "answer": "deserve, deserving, merited",
    "answerDetails": "You really don’t deserve to run the store."
  },
  {
    "id": 3549,
    "question": "cuadra",
    "questionDetails": "Buscamos alrededor de la cuadra.",
    "answer": "block",
    "answerDetails": "Looked around the block."
  },
  {
    "id": 3550,
    "question": "arrepiento",
    "questionDetails": "No me arrepiento de nada .",
    "answer": "regret, repent",
    "answerDetails": "I regret for nothing."
  },
  {
    "id": 3551,
    "question": "marcar",
    "questionDetails": "Cuelga el auricular y vuelva a marcar.",
    "answer": "dial, flag",
    "answerDetails": "Hang up and dial again."
  },
  {
    "id": 3552,
    "question": "vendió",
    "questionDetails": "Glenn se va a comprar un coche nuevo. Vendió el viejo la semana pasada.",
    "answer": "he sold",
    "answerDetails": "Glenn is going to buy a new car. He sold the old one last week."
  },
  {
    "id": 3553,
    "question": "rumbo",
    "questionDetails": "El gobierno tuvo que cambiar el rumbo de su política de austeridad.",
    "answer": "course, direction, bearing",
    "answerDetails": "The government was forced to change course on its austerity policy."
  },
  {
    "id": 3554,
    "question": "asumir",
    "questionDetails": "Él comenzó a asumir en sus ojos un aspecto romántico.",
    "answer": "assume",
    "answerDetails": "He began to assume in their eyes a romantic aspect."
  },
  {
    "id": 3555,
    "question": "bonitos",
    "questionDetails": "También sus gatos son muy bonitos.",
    "answer": "beautiful, pretty, cute",
    "answerDetails": "His cats are beautiful too."
  },
  {
    "id": 3556,
    "question": "preocupados",
    "questionDetails": "Sus familiares están preocupados.",
    "answer": "worried, concerned, apprehensive",
    "answerDetails": "Your relatives are worried."
  },
  {
    "id": 3557,
    "question": "circo",
    "questionDetails": "El circo viaja de ciudad en Ciudad para montar su espectáculo.",
    "answer": "circus, cirque",
    "answerDetails": "The circus travels from city to city to put on their performance."
  },
  {
    "id": 3558,
    "question": "ciertas",
    "questionDetails": "Hay ciertas cosas que jamás sabremos.",
    "answer": "certain, true",
    "answerDetails": "There are certain things we shall never know."
  },
  {
    "id": 3559,
    "question": "revisando",
    "questionDetails": "Pongo mi navaja, revisando la graduación.",
    "answer": "reviewing, checking, rechecking",
    "answerDetails": "I put my knife, reviewing graduation."
  },
  {
    "id": 3560,
    "question": "descubrió",
    "questionDetails": "Descubrió lo que había hecho Marco y lo dejó.",
    "answer": "she found out",
    "answerDetails": "She found out what Marco had done and left him."
  },
  {
    "id": 3561,
    "question": "grano",
    "questionDetails": "Si el azúcar hace el grano para arriba, agregue más agua.",
    "answer": "grain, corn, seed",
    "answerDetails": "If the sugar does grain up, add more water."
  },
  {
    "id": 3562,
    "question": "mandas",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando llegues a la base, me los mandas.",
    "answer": "send",
    "answerDetails": "When you get backto the base, send it back."
  },
  {
    "id": 3563,
    "question": "enterrar",
    "questionDetails": "Vine ante ustedes para enterrar al hombre.",
    "answer": "bury",
    "answerDetails": "I come before you now to bury the man."
  },
  {
    "id": 3564,
    "question": "dirás",
    "questionDetails": "Promete que no lo dirás.",
    "answer": "tell",
    "answerDetails": "Please just promise you won’t tell."
  },
  {
    "id": 3565,
    "question": "valen",
    "questionDetails": "Diez autos no valen la pena el esfuerzo.",
    "answer": "worth",
    "answerDetails": "Ten cars is hardly worth the effort."
  },
  {
    "id": 3566,
    "question": "directa",
    "questionDetails": "Puede que no sea capaz de comunicación directa.",
    "answer": "direct",
    "answerDetails": "It may not be capable of direct communication."
  },
  {
    "id": 3567,
    "question": "piensen",
    "questionDetails": "Les pedimos que lo piensen.",
    "answer": "think",
    "answerDetails": "Asked them that they think it."
  },
  {
    "id": 3568,
    "question": "contaron",
    "questionDetails": "Le contaron a su mamá sobre la nueva principal en la escuela.",
    "answer": "they told",
    "answerDetails": "They told their mother about the new principal at the school."
  },
  {
    "id": 3569,
    "question": "supieras",
    "questionDetails": "Suenas como si supieras algo de esto.",
    "answer": "know",
    "answerDetails": "You sound like you know something about it."
  },
  {
    "id": 3570,
    "question": "vendido",
    "questionDetails": "Más de la mitad de los apartamentos del edificio nuevo ya están vendidos.",
    "answer": "sold",
    "answerDetails": "More than half of the apartments in the new building are already sold."
  },
  {
    "id": 3571,
    "question": "abandonado",
    "questionDetails": "Un baile salvaje y abandonado.",
    "answer": "abandoned, derelict",
    "answerDetails": "A wild, abandoned dance."
  },
  {
    "id": 3572,
    "question": "sufrimiento",
    "questionDetails": "Poca gente ha padecido tanto sufrimiento como él.",
    "answer": "suffering, distress, misery",
    "answerDetails": "Few people have experienced such suffering as he has."
  },
  {
    "id": 3573,
    "question": "podremos",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que podremos hacerlo.",
    "answer": "can",
    "answerDetails": "I think we can handle that."
  },
  {
    "id": 3574,
    "question": "jugamos",
    "questionDetails": "Ayer, jugamos fútbol en la escuela.",
    "answer": "we played",
    "answerDetails": "Yesterday, we played soccer at school."
  },
  {
    "id": 3575,
    "question": "fotografía",
    "questionDetails": "Entiendo que te interesa la fotografía.",
    "answer": "photography",
    "answerDetails": "I understand you have an interest in photography."
  },
  {
    "id": 3576,
    "question": "entras",
    "questionDetails": "Abandona toda esperanza, tu que entras aquí.",
    "answer": "enter",
    "answerDetails": "Abandon all hope, ye who enter here."
  },
  {
    "id": 3577,
    "question": "presentado",
    "questionDetails": "Ese asunto será presentado ante el comité de disciplina.",
    "answer": "presented, submitted, filed",
    "answerDetails": "This matter will be presented to the disciplinary committee."
  },
  {
    "id": 3578,
    "question": "alarma",
    "questionDetails": "Señal de alarma.",
    "answer": "alarm",
    "answerDetails": "Alarm signal."
  },
  {
    "id": 3579,
    "question": "muestras",
    "questionDetails": "Aquí tiene las muestras.",
    "answer": "samples, signs, specimens",
    "answerDetails": "Here it has the samples."
  },
  {
    "id": 3580,
    "question": "piezas",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo dos grupos de piezas de metal similares.",
    "answer": "parts, pieces, pcs",
    "answerDetails": "I have two sets of similar metal parts."
  },
  {
    "id": 3581,
    "question": "camiseta",
    "questionDetails": "La camiseta del equipo es blanca y azul.",
    "answer": "shirt, jersey, tee",
    "answerDetails": "The team shirt is white and blue."
  },
  {
    "id": 3582,
    "question": "firmes",
    "questionDetails": "Si nos mantenemos firmes, no será el último.",
    "answer": "firm, steady, sign",
    "answerDetails": "If we hold firm, it won’t be the last."
  },
  {
    "id": 3583,
    "question": "harás",
    "answer": "stud"
  },
  {
    "id": 3584,
    "question": "daré",
    "answer": "Give"
  },
  {
    "id": 3585,
    "question": "guardo",
    "questionDetails": "Lo guardo en el agujero.",
    "answer": "keep",
    "answerDetails": "Keep it in the hole."
  },
  {
    "id": 3586,
    "question": "abiertos",
    "questionDetails": "Ojos y oídos abiertos.",
    "answer": "open",
    "answerDetails": "Eyes and ears open."
  },
  {
    "id": 3587,
    "question": "antecedentes",
    "questionDetails": "Antecedentes de la exposición, patrones de excavaciones arqueológicas.",
    "answer": "background",
    "answerDetails": "Background of the exhibit, patrons of archaeological digs."
  },
  {
    "id": 3588,
    "question": "cambiamos",
    "questionDetails": "Así que lo cambiamos.",
    "answer": "switched, change, swap",
    "answerDetails": "So we switched it out."
  },
  {
    "id": 3589,
    "question": "labios",
    "questionDetails": "Su voz, sus ojos sus manos, sus labios.",
    "answer": "lips",
    "answerDetails": "Your voice, your eyes your hands, your lips."
  },
  {
    "id": 3590,
    "question": "escapa",
    "questionDetails": "Nadie se me escapa.",
    "answer": "escapes, run away, flees",
    "answerDetails": "No one escapes me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3591,
    "question": "cargado",
    "questionDetails": "Programa cargado y listo.",
    "answer": "loaded",
    "answerDetails": "Program loaded and ready."
  },
  {
    "id": 3592,
    "question": "mercancía",
    "questionDetails": "Hay que asegurarse que la mercancía no se estropeé.",
    "answer": "goods, commodity, merchandise",
    "answerDetails": "We must ensure the goods don’t spoil."
  },
  {
    "id": 3593,
    "question": "gol",
    "questionDetails": "Pumas le ganó a Chivas con un marcador de 3 goles a uno.",
    "answer": "goal",
    "answerDetails": "Pumas beat Chivas by a score of three goals to one."
  },
  {
    "id": 3594,
    "question": "fiscal",
    "questionDetails": "El Congreso quiere reformar el sistema fiscal.",
    "answer": "tax, prosecutor",
    "answerDetails": "Congress wants to reform the tax system."
  },
  {
    "id": 3595,
    "question": "bronca",
    "questionDetails": "… algún otro lugar tienes dolor y bronca.",
    "answer": "anger",
    "answerDetails": "… somewhere you have pain and anger."
  },
  {
    "id": 3596,
    "question": "república",
    "questionDetails": "El resultado es una república.",
    "answer": "republic",
    "answerDetails": "The result to be a republic."
  },
  {
    "id": 3597,
    "question": "pobrecita",
    "questionDetails": "Pobrecita de mi madre.",
    "answer": "poor",
    "answerDetails": "Poor mother of mine."
  },
  {
    "id": 3598,
    "question": "canciones",
    "questionDetails": "Y ambos tienen canciones brillantes.",
    "answer": "songs, tunes, tracks",
    "answerDetails": "And you both have brilliant songs."
  },
  {
    "id": 3599,
    "question": "quietos",
    "questionDetails": "Los árboles están muy quietos.",
    "answer": "still, freeze",
    "answerDetails": "The trees are so still."
  },
  {
    "id": 3600,
    "question": "amas",
    "questionDetails": "Tienes que seguirlo, Teresa. Lo amas.",
    "answer": "you love him",
    "answerDetails": "You have to go after him, Teresa. You love him."
  },
  {
    "id": 3601,
    "question": "extrañar",
    "questionDetails": "Imposible extrañar a alguien que llevarás siempre en el corazón.",
    "answer": "miss, surprising, wondered",
    "answerDetails": "Impossible to miss someone who will always be in heart."
  },
  {
    "id": 3602,
    "question": "matarlo",
    "questionDetails": "Si viene cerca de mi familia, voy a matarlo.",
    "answer": "kill him",
    "answerDetails": "If he comes near my family, I’m going to kill him."
  },
  {
    "id": 3603,
    "question": "entregó",
    "questionDetails": "Basados en evidencia fabricada que ella les entregó.",
    "answer": "handed, delivered, handed over",
    "answerDetails": "Based on fabricated evidence that she handed to them."
  },
  {
    "id": 3604,
    "question": "regresó",
    "questionDetails": "Y un mes dejó la casa y no regresó.",
    "answer": "returned",
    "answerDetails": "And then one month he left home and never returned."
  },
  {
    "id": 3605,
    "question": "bárbaro",
    "questionDetails": "Gertrude es tan refinada que nos quedamos todos pasmados ante el bárbaro comportamiento de sus hijos.",
    "answer": "barbarian, barbaric",
    "answerDetails": "Gertrude is so refined that we were all stunned by her children’s barbarian behavior."
  },
  {
    "id": 3606,
    "question": "santos",
    "answer": "Santos, saints, holy ones"
  },
  {
    "id": 3607,
    "question": "manejo",
    "questionDetails": "Su manejo de la situación fue excepcional.",
    "answer": "management, handling, operation",
    "answerDetails": "His management of the situation was exceptional."
  },
  {
    "id": 3608,
    "question": "demonio",
    "questionDetails": "La monja fue poseída por un demonio y aterrorizó al pueblo durante semanas.",
    "answer": "demon, devil, fiend",
    "answerDetails": "The nun was possessed by a demon and terrorized the town for weeks."
  },
  {
    "id": 3609,
    "question": "leyes",
    "questionDetails": "Las leyes de privacidad son super estrictas ahora.",
    "answer": "laws, legislation",
    "answerDetails": "Because privacy laws are super strict nowadays."
  },
  {
    "id": 3610,
    "question": "conocerlo",
    "questionDetails": "Usted tiene que conocerlo.",
    "answer": "know",
    "answerDetails": "You must know her."
  },
  {
    "id": 3611,
    "question": "ponernos",
    "questionDetails": "Ponernos ciegos, e irnos por ahí en barca.",
    "answer": "get",
    "answerDetails": "Get loaded, and take the boat out."
  },
  {
    "id": 3612,
    "question": "ministerio",
    "questionDetails": "Él está entrenando para el Ministerio.",
    "answer": "ministry",
    "answerDetails": "He is training for the ministry."
  },
  {
    "id": 3613,
    "question": "ilusiones",
    "questionDetails": "El idealismo no es algo malo, pero hacerse demasiadas ilusiones no llevará a ningún cambio.",
    "answer": "wishful thinking",
    "answerDetails": "Idealism isn’t a bad thing, but too much wishful thinking won’t lead to any change."
  },
  {
    "id": 3614,
    "question": "conseguiste",
    "questionDetails": "¿Conseguiste trabajo finalmente? ¡ Felicitaciones!.",
    "answer": "did you get, you got",
    "answerDetails": "Did you get a job finally? Congratulations!."
  },
  {
    "id": 3615,
    "question": "sacarte",
    "questionDetails": "Tienes que sacarte tus zapatos.",
    "answer": "take",
    "answerDetails": "You gotta take those shoes off."
  },
  {
    "id": 3616,
    "question": "sana",
    "questionDetails": "Fue una relación completamente legal y sana.",
    "answer": "healthy, heals, sound",
    "answerDetails": "It was a totally legal and healthy relationship."
  },
  {
    "id": 3617,
    "question": "abrí",
    "questionDetails": "Abrí la puerta, y el gato entró.",
    "answer": "i opened",
    "answerDetails": "I opened the door, and the cat came in."
  },
  {
    "id": 3618,
    "question": "adivina",
    "questionDetails": "La adivina le dijo a la mujer que tendría 4 hijos varones.",
    "answer": "diviner",
    "answerDetails": "The diviner told the woman that she’d have four sons."
  },
  {
    "id": 3619,
    "question": "mientas",
    "questionDetails": "Espero que le mientas a tus padres mejor que eso.",
    "answer": "lie",
    "answerDetails": "I hope you lie to your parents better than that."
  },
  {
    "id": 3620,
    "question": "ayuden",
    "questionDetails": "No tengo amigos que me ayuden.",
    "answer": "help, assist",
    "answerDetails": "I have no friends to help me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3621,
    "question": "inversión",
    "questionDetails": "Esta pregunta requiere una inversión entre el sujeto y el verbo.",
    "answer": "inversion",
    "answerDetails": "This question requires the inversion of the subject and verb."
  },
  {
    "id": 3622,
    "question": "graves",
    "questionDetails": "La barra que desear cuando se trata de graves.",
    "answer": "bass",
    "answerDetails": "The bar lacking when it comes to bass."
  },
  {
    "id": 3623,
    "question": "dispara",
    "questionDetails": "Dispara a las alas.",
    "answer": "shoot, fires, triggers",
    "answerDetails": "Shoot the wings off the flies."
  },
  {
    "id": 3624,
    "question": "culpables",
    "questionDetails": "Nos sentimos tan culpables.",
    "answer": "guilty, culprits, blame",
    "answerDetails": "We feel so guilty."
  },
  {
    "id": 3625,
    "question": "decirnos",
    "questionDetails": "Ese anciano piensa que puede decirnos qué hacer.",
    "answer": "tell us",
    "answerDetails": "That old man thinks he can tell us what to do."
  },
  {
    "id": 3626,
    "question": "pierdes",
    "questionDetails": "Si no tú pierdes.",
    "answer": "lose",
    "answerDetails": "If not you lose."
  },
  {
    "id": 3627,
    "question": "avisó",
    "questionDetails": "Fue su espíritu quien te avisó.",
    "answer": "warned, alerted, tipped",
    "answerDetails": "It was her spirit that warned you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3628,
    "question": "límites",
    "questionDetails": "La estupidez de algunos parece no tener límites.",
    "answer": "bounds",
    "answerDetails": "The stupidity of some people appears to know no bounds."
  },
  {
    "id": 3629,
    "question": "medias",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Qué frío hace! ¡ Ojalá llevara medias gruesas!.",
    "answer": "tights, hosiery",
    "answerDetails": "It’s really cold today! I wish I was wearing thick tights!."
  },
  {
    "id": 3630,
    "question": "mochila",
    "questionDetails": "Roger se detuvo al lado del sendero para sacar un tentempié de su mochila.",
    "answer": "rucksack",
    "answerDetails": "Roger stopped on the side of the trail to get a small snack out of his rucksack."
  },
  {
    "id": 3631,
    "question": "lágrimas",
    "questionDetails": "No ha habido lágrimas.",
    "answer": "tears",
    "answerDetails": "There had been no tears."
  },
  {
    "id": 3632,
    "question": "cogido",
    "questionDetails": "Lo ha cogido al volver de la escuela.",
    "answer": "caught, picked up, grabbed",
    "answerDetails": "Caught it coming home from school."
  },
  {
    "id": 3633,
    "question": "preparo",
    "questionDetails": "Yo preparo sus comidas.",
    "answer": "prepare",
    "answerDetails": "I prepare her meals."
  },
  {
    "id": 3634,
    "question": "valores",
    "questionDetails": "Es una buena chica con muy sólidos valores.",
    "answer": "values, securities",
    "answerDetails": "She’s a good girl with a strong set of values."
  },
  {
    "id": 3635,
    "question": "ciego",
    "questionDetails": "Tratan de ciegos con la ciencia.",
    "answer": "blind, caecum",
    "answerDetails": "They try to blind you with science."
  },
  {
    "id": 3636,
    "question": "casé",
    "questionDetails": "Me casé con el primero que me miró.",
    "answer": "married, get married",
    "answerDetails": "I married the first man who looked at me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3637,
    "question": "colegas",
    "questionDetails": "Un par de mis colegas.",
    "answer": "colleagues, peers, buddies",
    "answerDetails": "A couple colleagues of mine."
  },
  {
    "id": 3638,
    "question": "favorita",
    "questionDetails": "Mi hermana siempre fue la favorita de nuestros padres.",
    "answer": "favorite",
    "answerDetails": "My sister was always my parents’ favorite."
  },
  {
    "id": 3639,
    "question": "marcas",
    "questionDetails": "Sí, de las mismas marcas y lo antes posible.",
    "answer": "brands, marks, trademarks",
    "answerDetails": "The same brands, and as soon as possible."
  },
  {
    "id": 3640,
    "question": "plazo",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero un préstamo de corto plazo.",
    "answer": "term, period, deadline",
    "answerDetails": "I want a short-term loan."
  },
  {
    "id": 3641,
    "question": "pulso",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando te despiertes, pero antes de levantarte, mira tu pulso en Reposo.",
    "answer": "pulse",
    "answerDetails": "When you wake up, but before you get out of bed, check your resting pulse."
  },
  {
    "id": 3642,
    "question": "copas",
    "questionDetails": "Incluso las aguas en cuencos y copas.",
    "answer": "cups, glasses, drinks",
    "answerDetails": "Even waters in bowls and cups."
  },
  {
    "id": 3643,
    "question": "caí",
    "questionDetails": "Me caí y me golpeé.",
    "answer": "fell, dawned, crashed",
    "answerDetails": "I fell and hurt myself."
  },
  {
    "id": 3644,
    "question": "seco",
    "questionDetails": "La Costa Oeste ha tenido 2 inviernos secos en una fila.",
    "answer": "dry, dried",
    "answerDetails": "The West Coast has had two dry winters in a row."
  },
  {
    "id": 3645,
    "question": "caída",
    "questionDetails": "La caída de la red de la compañía retrasó el lanzamiento del nuevo software.",
    "answer": "crash, dropping, hang",
    "answerDetails": "The crash of the company’s network delayed the release of the new software."
  },
  {
    "id": 3646,
    "question": "entenderlo",
    "questionDetails": "Pero ha de entenderlo.",
    "answer": "understand",
    "answerDetails": "But he’s got to understand."
  },
  {
    "id": 3647,
    "question": "obtener",
    "questionDetails": "Estamos dispuestos a obtener un récord.",
    "answer": "get, obtain",
    "answerDetails": "We’re keen to get a record out."
  },
  {
    "id": 3648,
    "question": "lógica",
    "questionDetails": "Antes de que digas que no, déjanos explicarte la lógica de la propuesta.",
    "answer": "rationale, logic",
    "answerDetails": "Before you say no, let us explain the rationale behind the proposal."
  },
  {
    "id": 3649,
    "question": "nace",
    "questionDetails": "El Orinoco es un enorme río venezolano. Nace en la sierra de Parima.",
    "answer": "it begins",
    "answerDetails": "The Orinoco is a huge Venezuelan river. It begins in the Parima Mountains."
  },
  {
    "id": 3650,
    "question": "cientos",
    "questionDetails": "Cientos de millones de dólares.",
    "answer": "hundreds, thousands",
    "answerDetails": "Hundreds of millions of dollars."
  },
  {
    "id": 3651,
    "question": "cajón",
    "questionDetails": "La engrapadora está en el cajón superior izquierdo.",
    "answer": "drawer",
    "answerDetails": "The stapler is in the top left drawer."
  },
  {
    "id": 3652,
    "question": "pequeñas",
    "questionDetails": "Disfruto la satisfacción de hacer bien las cosas pequeñas.",
    "answer": "small, little, tiny",
    "answerDetails": "I enjoy the satisfaction of doing small things well."
  },
  {
    "id": 3653,
    "question": "tendrían",
    "questionDetails": "Si hubieran ido al supermercado, como sugerí, tendrían todos los ingredientes del pastel.",
    "answer": "they would have",
    "answerDetails": "If they’d gone to the grocery store, as I suggested, they would have all the ingredients for the cake."
  },
  {
    "id": 3654,
    "question": "nacimiento",
    "questionDetails": "También descendió la tasa de nacimiento.",
    "answer": "birth",
    "answerDetails": "Also the birth rates lowered."
  },
  {
    "id": 3655,
    "question": "político",
    "questionDetails": "Como político, me supera hasta a mí.",
    "answer": "politician",
    "answerDetails": "As a politician he exceeds even myself."
  },
  {
    "id": 3656,
    "question": "celosa",
    "questionDetails": "Solo estabas celosa cuando él estaba fuera.",
    "answer": "jealous",
    "answerDetails": "You were only jealous when he was away."
  },
  {
    "id": 3657,
    "question": "gonzález",
    "answer": "Gonzalez"
  },
  {
    "id": 3658,
    "question": "ratas",
    "questionDetails": "Pero no es para tus ratas.",
    "answer": "rats, mice",
    "answerDetails": "But it is not for your rats."
  },
  {
    "id": 3659,
    "question": "lleguen",
    "questionDetails": "Pero cambiará cuando lleguen mis hijos.",
    "answer": "arrive, reach",
    "answerDetails": "But that will all change when my sons arrive."
  },
  {
    "id": 3660,
    "question": "bendito",
    "questionDetails": "Ha sido un bendito alivio.",
    "answer": "blessed",
    "answerDetails": "It was a blessed release."
  },
  {
    "id": 3661,
    "question": "presa",
    "questionDetails": "Abrieron la puerta de la presa para soltar el agua.",
    "answer": "dam, prey, reservoir",
    "answerDetails": "They opened the dam’s gate to let the water flow."
  },
  {
    "id": 3662,
    "question": "colmo",
    "questionDetails": "El colmo en los árboles verdes profundos creció orquídeas coloridas.",
    "answer": "high",
    "answerDetails": "High in the deep green trees grew colorful orchids."
  },
  {
    "id": 3663,
    "question": "huyendo",
    "questionDetails": "La gente está huyendo de la ciudad.",
    "answer": "fleeing, running, escaping",
    "answerDetails": "People are fleeing the city."
  },
  {
    "id": 3664,
    "question": "condena",
    "questionDetails": "Tiene condenas previas, pero lleva 15 años fuera de la prisión y sin consumir sustancias ni alcohol.",
    "answer": "conviction, sentence, condemnation",
    "answerDetails": "He has prior convictions, but he’s been out of prison and clean and sober for 15 years."
  },
  {
    "id": 3665,
    "question": "representante",
    "questionDetails": "No es muy buen representante.",
    "answer": "agent",
    "answerDetails": "Not a very good agent."
  },
  {
    "id": 3666,
    "question": "prometió",
    "answer": "Promised"
  },
  {
    "id": 3667,
    "question": "creerlo",
    "questionDetails": "Oímos que la tienda había cerrado pero no podíamos creerlo.",
    "answer": "believe it",
    "answerDetails": "We heard the store had closed down but couldn’t believe it."
  },
  {
    "id": 3668,
    "question": "porfa",
    "answer": "Porfa"
  },
  {
    "id": 3669,
    "question": "sois",
    "questionDetails": "Para mí, vosotros dos sois.",
    "answer": "are, thou art",
    "answerDetails": "For me you two are."
  },
  {
    "id": 3670,
    "question": "fábrica",
    "questionDetails": "La empresa tiene programado abrir nuevas fábricas en China.",
    "answer": "plant, mill, factory",
    "answerDetails": "The company plans to open new plants in China."
  },
  {
    "id": 3671,
    "question": "huir",
    "questionDetails": "Se vio obligado a huir del país.",
    "answer": "flee, escape",
    "answerDetails": "He was forced to flee the country."
  },
  {
    "id": 3672,
    "question": "rastro",
    "questionDetails": "No se puede caminar por la nieve sin dejar algún rastro.",
    "answer": "trace, trail",
    "answerDetails": "You cannot walk on snow without leaving some trace."
  },
  {
    "id": 3673,
    "question": "amenazó",
    "questionDetails": "Él amenazó a mi vida en realidad.",
    "answer": "threatened",
    "answerDetails": "He threatened my life actually."
  },
  {
    "id": 3674,
    "question": "celebrando",
    "questionDetails": "Pensó que debía estar celebrando algo.",
    "answer": "celebrating, welcoming",
    "answerDetails": "She thought she must be celebrating something."
  },
  {
    "id": 3675,
    "question": "universo",
    "questionDetails": "Necesito más que rocio y jugo de universo.",
    "answer": "universe",
    "answerDetails": "I need lot more than dew and the universe juice."
  },
  {
    "id": 3676,
    "question": "sagrado",
    "questionDetails": "A un oficial de policía nada es sagrado.",
    "answer": "sacred, holy, hallowed",
    "answerDetails": "To a police officer nothing is sacred."
  },
  {
    "id": 3677,
    "question": "amenazas",
    "questionDetails": "Durante el desayuno siempre recibo amenazas graves.",
    "answer": "threats, menaces, threatened",
    "answerDetails": "I get serious threats every morning."
  },
  {
    "id": 3678,
    "question": "importar",
    "questionDetails": "Decidir cómo desea importar el sonido.",
    "answer": "import",
    "answerDetails": "Decide how you want to import sound."
  },
  {
    "id": 3679,
    "question": "acostumbrada",
    "questionDetails": "Ya veo que está acostumbrada a la buena vida.",
    "answer": "accustomed, used, wonted",
    "answerDetails": "I can tell you’re accustomed to fine living."
  },
  {
    "id": 3680,
    "question": "acerques",
    "questionDetails": "No te acerques al bar.",
    "answer": "near",
    "answerDetails": "Do not go near the bar."
  },
  {
    "id": 3681,
    "question": "bosque",
    "questionDetails": "¿Quieres dar un paseo por el bosque?",
    "answer": "woods, woodland",
    "answerDetails": "Do you want to take a walk through the woods?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3682,
    "question": "testimonio",
    "questionDetails": "Si das testimonio falso, te puedan acusar de haber cometido perjurio.",
    "answer": "witness, testament",
    "answerDetails": "If you bear false witness, you can be accused of having committed perjury."
  },
  {
    "id": 3683,
    "question": "sacan",
    "questionDetails": "Entonces le sacan la venda.",
    "answer": "take",
    "answerDetails": "Then they take the blindfold off."
  },
  {
    "id": 3684,
    "question": "pasillo",
    "questionDetails": "El pasillo era largo y estaba mal iluminado.",
    "answer": "hallway, corridor, aisle",
    "answerDetails": "The hallway was long and poorly lit."
  },
  {
    "id": 3685,
    "question": "cumpla",
    "questionDetails": "Cumpla mis demandas en el plazo de una hora o …",
    "answer": "comply, meet, conforms",
    "answerDetails": "Comply with my demands within the hour, or …"
  },
  {
    "id": 3686,
    "question": "cercano",
    "questionDetails": "Ella dijo que hay un patio de recreo cercano.",
    "answer": "nearby",
    "answerDetails": "She said there’s a playground nearby."
  },
  {
    "id": 3687,
    "question": "verlas",
    "questionDetails": "Nos alegramos tanto de verlas.",
    "answer": "see",
    "answerDetails": "We are so happy to see you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3688,
    "question": "traemos",
    "questionDetails": "Traemos más al grupo.",
    "answer": "bring",
    "answerDetails": "Bring more into the fold."
  },
  {
    "id": 3689,
    "question": "arrancar",
    "questionDetails": "Una revolución es necesaria para arrancar el orden social.",
    "answer": "uproot",
    "answerDetails": "A revolution is necessary to uproot the social order."
  },
  {
    "id": 3690,
    "question": "encontrarme",
    "answer": "Meet"
  },
  {
    "id": 3691,
    "question": "soñé",
    "questionDetails": "Tan sólo nunca soñé.",
    "answer": "dreamed",
    "answerDetails": "I just never dreamed."
  },
  {
    "id": 3692,
    "question": "suficientemente",
    "questionDetails": "María dice que sale con hombres mayores, ya que los hombres de su edad no son suficientemente maduros.",
    "answer": "sufficiently, adequately",
    "answerDetails": "Maria says she dates older men, because men her age are not sufficiently mature."
  },
  {
    "id": 3693,
    "question": "aprovecha",
    "questionDetails": "Rainfinity aprovecha los estándares de la industria sin la introducción …",
    "answer": "leverages, take advantage, exploits",
    "answerDetails": "Rainfinity leverages industry standards without introducing …"
  },
  {
    "id": 3694,
    "question": "arrepentido",
    "questionDetails": "El acusado fue arrepentido por lo que había hecho.",
    "answer": "remorseful",
    "answerDetails": "The defendant was remorseful for what he had done."
  },
  {
    "id": 3695,
    "question": "hombro",
    "questionDetails": "Me disloqué el hombro al caerme del caballo.",
    "answer": "shoulder",
    "answerDetails": "I dislocated my shoulder when I fell from my horse."
  },
  {
    "id": 3696,
    "question": "pantalla",
    "questionDetails": "Su pelo giró a través de la pantalla de su cara.",
    "answer": "screen, display",
    "answerDetails": "Her hair swung across to screen her face."
  },
  {
    "id": 3697,
    "question": "profesión",
    "questionDetails": "De profesión.",
    "answer": "profession",
    "answerDetails": "By profession."
  },
  {
    "id": 3698,
    "question": "montado",
    "questionDetails": "Y que se hubiesen montado en el mismo tren que la …",
    "answer": "mounted",
    "answerDetails": "And that had mounted in the same train that the …"
  },
  {
    "id": 3699,
    "question": "platos",
    "questionDetails": "¿Ya lavaste los platos?",
    "answer": "dishes",
    "answerDetails": "Did you wash the dishes already?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3700,
    "question": "enseñado",
    "answer": "trained"
  },
  {
    "id": 3701,
    "question": "pongamos",
    "questionDetails": "Pongamos un parche ahí.",
    "answer": "put",
    "answerDetails": "Put a bandage on it."
  },
  {
    "id": 3702,
    "question": "popular",
    "questionDetails": "Disfrutamos escuchando música popular en vivo en nuestro viaje a la Sierra de Chiapas.",
    "answer": "folk",
    "answerDetails": "We enjoyed listening to live folk music on our trip to the mountains of Chiapas."
  },
  {
    "id": 3703,
    "question": "saldrá",
    "questionDetails": "Mucha gente saldrá lastimada.",
    "answer": "will",
    "answerDetails": "Many people will hurt."
  },
  {
    "id": 3704,
    "question": "querría",
    "questionDetails": "Si estuviera viviendo en una clima fría, querría ir de vacaciones en el Caribe.",
    "answer": "i would want",
    "answerDetails": "If I was living in a cold climate, I would want to take vacations in the Caribbean."
  },
  {
    "id": 3705,
    "question": "relacionado",
    "questionDetails": "La policía cree que estos casos de violencia pudieran ser relacionados.",
    "answer": "related, linked, connected",
    "answerDetails": "Police think that these instances of violence may be related."
  },
  {
    "id": 3706,
    "question": "saltar",
    "questionDetails": "Es una película de acción tan rápido que amenaza con saltar los rieles.",
    "answer": "jump, leap, pounce",
    "answerDetails": "It’s an action movie so fast it threatens to jump the rails."
  },
  {
    "id": 3707,
    "question": "pondría",
    "questionDetails": "Yo me pondría en tu lugar cualquier día.",
    "answer": "would",
    "answerDetails": "I would take your seat any day."
  },
  {
    "id": 3708,
    "question": "adelantado",
    "questionDetails": "Tienes un intelecto muy adelantado.",
    "answer": "advanced",
    "answerDetails": "You are a truly advanced intellect."
  },
  {
    "id": 3709,
    "question": "aproximadamente",
    "questionDetails": "El ser humano medio está compuesto aproximadamente de un 65% de agua.",
    "answer": "approximately, about, roughly",
    "answerDetails": "The average human is approximately 65% water."
  },
  {
    "id": 3710,
    "question": "representa",
    "answer": "Represents"
  },
  {
    "id": 3711,
    "question": "probado",
    "questionDetails": "Trato de evitar comprar champús probados en animales.",
    "answer": "tested, tried, proven",
    "answerDetails": "I try to avoid buying shampoos tested on animals."
  },
  {
    "id": 3712,
    "question": "izquierdo",
    "questionDetails": "Se rompió el brazo izquierdo jugando baloncesto.",
    "answer": "left",
    "answerDetails": "She broke her left arm playing basketball."
  },
  {
    "id": 3713,
    "question": "guía",
    "questionDetails": "Esta guía de guitarra es una valiosa herramienta para la enseñanza y el aprendizaje de este instrumento.",
    "answer": "companion",
    "answerDetails": "This guitar companion is a valuable tool for teaching and learning this instrument."
  },
  {
    "id": 3714,
    "question": "colombia",
    "answer": "Colombia, Columbia, Colombian"
  },
  {
    "id": 3715,
    "question": "oyó",
    "questionDetails": "Oyó algo acerca de mi revisión médica?",
    "answer": "heard, overheard",
    "answerDetails": "Heard anything about my medical?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3716,
    "question": "podés",
    "questionDetails": "Te podés quedar una semana.",
    "answer": "can",
    "answerDetails": "You can stay here one week."
  },
  {
    "id": 3717,
    "question": "marta",
    "questionDetails": "La Marta hizo su manida en un árbol hueco.",
    "answer": "marten",
    "answerDetails": "The Marten made its den in a hollow tree."
  },
  {
    "id": 3718,
    "question": "cállese",
    "questionDetails": "Muéstreme pruebas o cállese.",
    "answer": "shut up",
    "answerDetails": "Produce proof or shut up."
  },
  {
    "id": 3719,
    "question": "celda",
    "questionDetails": "Tiene una estructura hexagonal, como las celdas de un panal.",
    "answer": "cell",
    "answerDetails": "It has a hexagonal structure, just like the cells of a honeycomb."
  },
  {
    "id": 3720,
    "question": "sobrino",
    "questionDetails": "Mi sobrino me ha estado rogando que le consiga unas.",
    "answer": "nephew",
    "answerDetails": "My nephew’s been begging me for some."
  },
  {
    "id": 3721,
    "question": "delicioso",
    "questionDetails": "El sándwich estuvo delicioso.",
    "answer": "delicious",
    "answerDetails": "The sandwich was delicious."
  },
  {
    "id": 3722,
    "question": "cuide",
    "questionDetails": "No tengo a nadie que cuide de mi.",
    "answer": "take care, babysit",
    "answerDetails": "I have no one to take care of me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3723,
    "question": "lobo",
    "questionDetails": "Acabo de ser devorado por un lobo.",
    "answer": "wolf",
    "answerDetails": "I just got eaten by a wolf."
  },
  {
    "id": 3724,
    "question": "mandaste",
    "questionDetails": "Mandaste a mi asistente a hacer un encargo?",
    "answer": "sent",
    "answerDetails": "You sent my assistant on an errand?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3725,
    "question": "bajen",
    "questionDetails": "Bien, bajen la cesta cuando estén en posición.",
    "answer": "lower, lay down",
    "answerDetails": "Lower the basket as soon as you’re in position."
  },
  {
    "id": 3726,
    "question": "venís",
    "questionDetails": "Parece que venís bastante seguido estos días.",
    "answer": "come",
    "answerDetails": "So it seems you come often these days."
  },
  {
    "id": 3727,
    "question": "traté",
    "questionDetails": "Traté de que cambiara de opinión.",
    "answer": "tried, treated",
    "answerDetails": "I have tried to change her mind."
  },
  {
    "id": 3728,
    "question": "entierro",
    "questionDetails": "El día del entierro.",
    "answer": "interment, grave",
    "answerDetails": "The day of interment."
  },
  {
    "id": 3729,
    "question": "creyó",
    "questionDetails": "Frank es un poco ingenuo. Creyó todo lo que le dijo Mary sobre su familia.",
    "answer": "he believed",
    "answerDetails": "Frank is a bit naive. He believed everything Mary told him about her family."
  },
  {
    "id": 3730,
    "question": "monte",
    "questionDetails": "Las antenas de transmisión están en la cima del monte Wilson.",
    "answer": "mount, hill, bush",
    "answerDetails": "The transmitting antennas are atop Mount Wilson."
  },
  {
    "id": 3731,
    "question": "enamoré",
    "questionDetails": "Me enamoré de ti.",
    "answer": "fell",
    "answerDetails": "I fell for you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3732,
    "question": "sucia",
    "questionDetails": "Son gente muy sucia.",
    "answer": "dirty, filthy, soiled",
    "answerDetails": "These are dirty people."
  },
  {
    "id": 3733,
    "question": "ofreció",
    "questionDetails": "Me ofreció dinero extra para contratar a una cocinera.",
    "answer": "offered, featured, volunteered",
    "answerDetails": "Offered to give me extra money to hire a cook."
  },
  {
    "id": 3734,
    "question": "echamos",
    "questionDetails": "Y si echamos uno rápido, estupendo.",
    "answer": "we",
    "answerDetails": "And if we get a quickie in, good."
  },
  {
    "id": 3735,
    "question": "paraíso",
    "questionDetails": "Mi idea del Paraíso es relajarse en el paseo marítimo.",
    "answer": "paradise",
    "answerDetails": "My idea of paradise is to relax on the seafront."
  },
  {
    "id": 3736,
    "question": "pasaporte",
    "questionDetails": "Tenía un pasaporte falso con un nombre falso.",
    "answer": "passport",
    "answerDetails": "It contained a fake passport with a phony name."
  },
  {
    "id": 3737,
    "question": "decírselo",
    "questionDetails": "Un expediente no puede decírselo todo.",
    "answer": "tell",
    "answerDetails": "A file can’t tell you everything."
  },
  {
    "id": 3738,
    "question": "acompañas",
    "answer": "Join"
  },
  {
    "id": 3739,
    "question": "tremenda",
    "questionDetails": "Esta es una ventaja tremenda.",
    "answer": "tremendous, terrific, awful",
    "answerDetails": "This is a tremendous advantage."
  },
  {
    "id": 3740,
    "question": "consta",
    "questionDetails": "La caravana consta de dos partes.",
    "answer": "consists, comprises, composed",
    "answerDetails": "The caravan consists of two parts."
  },
  {
    "id": 3741,
    "question": "oficiales",
    "questionDetails": "Llame a los oficiales a cubierta.",
    "answer": "officers, official, formal",
    "answerDetails": "Assemble the officers on the starboard deck."
  },
  {
    "id": 3742,
    "question": "prometiste",
    "questionDetails": "Ya sabes, como lo prometiste hace una semana.",
    "answer": "promised",
    "answerDetails": "You know, like you promised, a week ago?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3743,
    "question": "buscó",
    "questionDetails": "Ni siquiera buscó mi nombre.",
    "answer": "sought, searched, hunted",
    "answerDetails": "He never even sought my name."
  },
  {
    "id": 3744,
    "question": "pum",
    "questionDetails": "Pum, ahí lo tienen.",
    "answer": "boom, poum, bam",
    "answerDetails": "Boom there it is."
  },
  {
    "id": 3745,
    "question": "helado",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero una bola de helado de fresa.",
    "answer": "ice cream, frosty",
    "answerDetails": "I want a scoop of Strawberry ice cream."
  },
  {
    "id": 3746,
    "question": "palacio",
    "answer": "centre"
  },
  {
    "id": 3747,
    "question": "actos",
    "questionDetails": "Son los actos anormales de una juventud sin frenos.",
    "answer": "acts, actions, deeds",
    "answerDetails": "Those are deviant acts of reckless youth."
  },
  {
    "id": 3748,
    "question": "parejas",
    "questionDetails": "Este es para parejas.",
    "answer": "couples, pairs, partners",
    "answerDetails": "This is for couples."
  },
  {
    "id": 3749,
    "question": "luchando",
    "questionDetails": "Luchando por un mundo decente.",
    "answer": "fighting, struggling, scrambling",
    "answerDetails": "Fighting for a decent world."
  },
  {
    "id": 3750,
    "question": "margen",
    "questionDetails": "Estos agricultores subsisten al margen de la economía nacional.",
    "answer": "margin, scope, sidelines",
    "answerDetails": "These farmers subsist on the margins of the country’s economy."
  },
  {
    "id": 3751,
    "question": "abandonó",
    "questionDetails": "Mi hermano me abandonó.",
    "answer": "abandoned, quitted, left",
    "answerDetails": "My brother abandoned me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3752,
    "question": "cubrir",
    "questionDetails": "Los helicópteros disparaban en dirección a la línea de árboles para cubrir el avance de las tropas terrestres.",
    "answer": "cover",
    "answerDetails": "The helicopters fired into the tree line to cover the advance of the ground troops."
  },
  {
    "id": 3753,
    "question": "tirada",
    "questionDetails": "Este va a ser un gran número que necesitará una tirada de 5, 000 ejemplares como mínimo.",
    "answer": "printing",
    "answerDetails": "This is going to be a big issue that will need a printing of at least 5,000 copies."
  },
  {
    "id": 3754,
    "question": "menores",
    "questionDetails": "Todos estos son problemas menores que son fácilmente corregidos.",
    "answer": "minor, juvenile, smaller",
    "answerDetails": "These are all minor problems that are easily corrected."
  },
  {
    "id": 3755,
    "question": "demuestra",
    "questionDetails": "Nos quedamos muy impresionados con la propuesta de Samuel. Demuestra la urgencia de mejorar la disponibilidad de Internet en la zona.",
    "answer": "it demonstrates",
    "answerDetails": "We were very impressed with Samuel’s proposal. It demonstrates the urgency of improving Internet provision in the area."
  },
  {
    "id": 3756,
    "question": "despertó",
    "questionDetails": "Luego, algo me despertó.",
    "answer": "awoke, woke, woke up",
    "answerDetails": "Then something awoke me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3757,
    "question": "humanidad",
    "questionDetails": "Atroces crímenes contra la humanidad.",
    "answer": "humanity, mankind",
    "answerDetails": "Appalling crimes against humanity."
  },
  {
    "id": 3758,
    "question": "visión",
    "questionDetails": "Mi visión no es tan buena como cuando era joven.",
    "answer": "vision",
    "answerDetails": "My vision is not as good as when I was younger."
  },
  {
    "id": 3759,
    "question": "once",
    "questionDetails": "Once llamadas en la última media hora.",
    "answer": "eleven",
    "answerDetails": "Eleven calls in the last half hour."
  },
  {
    "id": 3760,
    "question": "función",
    "questionDetails": "La considero cualificada para realizar esta función.",
    "answer": "role, mode",
    "answerDetails": "I believe her to be well qualified to carry out this role."
  },
  {
    "id": 3761,
    "question": "miran",
    "questionDetails": "Las órdenes se miran como atar y los pagos …",
    "answer": "regarded, look, stare",
    "answerDetails": "Orders are regarded as binding and payments …"
  },
  {
    "id": 3762,
    "question": "importe",
    "questionDetails": "Hemos recibido una factura por un importe de $750.",
    "answer": "amount",
    "answerDetails": "We have received a bill for the amount of $750."
  },
  {
    "id": 3763,
    "question": "cinturón",
    "questionDetails": "Dijo que uno de ellos tenía que trabajar; Eddie pensó que estaba por debajo del cinturón.",
    "answer": "belt, girdle",
    "answerDetails": "She said one of them had to work; Eddie thought that was below the belt."
  },
  {
    "id": 3764,
    "question": "miraba",
    "questionDetails": "Todas las noches miraba la luna y pensaba sobre su futuro.",
    "answer": "she looked, she watched",
    "answerDetails": "Every night she looked at the moon and thought about her future."
  },
  {
    "id": 3765,
    "question": "okay",
    "questionDetails": "Okay, y tu nombre es.",
    "answer": "ok",
    "answerDetails": "Ok, and your name is."
  },
  {
    "id": 3766,
    "question": "aló",
    "answer": "Hello"
  },
  {
    "id": 3767,
    "question": "mamita",
    "questionDetails": "Entiendes por qué mamita está enojada, ¿verdad?",
    "answer": "mommy, mama, mammy",
    "answerDetails": "You do understand why Mommy was mad, don’t you?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3768,
    "question": "fernando",
    "answer": "Fernando"
  },
  {
    "id": 3769,
    "question": "joda",
    "answer": "None"
  },
  {
    "id": 3770,
    "question": "che",
    "questionDetails": "Che, David, ¿dónde pusiste mis llaves?",
    "answer": "yo",
    "answerDetails": "Yo, David, where did you put my keys?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3771,
    "question": "hey",
    "questionDetails": "Hey, Ana, what time are your friends coming?",
    "answer": "che",
    "answerDetails": "Che, Ana, ¿a qué hora llegan tus amigos?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3772,
    "question": "hermanita",
    "questionDetails": "Esto sirve para una anulación, hermanita.",
    "answer": "sis, sister",
    "answerDetails": "This is grounds for annulment, sis."
  },
  {
    "id": 3773,
    "question": "hostia",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Hostia, qué fuerte! ¿Qué tiene ese trago?",
    "answer": "jesus",
    "answerDetails": "Jesus, that’s strong! What’s in that drink?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3774,
    "question": "lealtad",
    "questionDetails": "No hay lealtad más pura que la de un perro hacia su amo.",
    "answer": "loyalty, allegiance, fealty",
    "answerDetails": "There is no purer loyalty than that of a dog to his master."
  },
  {
    "id": 3775,
    "question": "suegra",
    "questionDetails": "… en el coche con mi suegra.",
    "answer": "mother",
    "answerDetails": "… up there with her mother."
  },
  {
    "id": 3776,
    "question": "intenciones",
    "questionDetails": "El criminal le confesó sus malas intenciones a su compañero de celda.",
    "answer": "designs",
    "answerDetails": "The criminal confessed his evil designs to his cellmate."
  },
  {
    "id": 3777,
    "question": "amenazando",
    "questionDetails": "Están amenazando al jefe de la estación.",
    "answer": "threatening, menacing",
    "answerDetails": "So they’re threatening the station agent."
  },
  {
    "id": 3778,
    "question": "entiendas",
    "questionDetails": "Espero que entiendas esto.",
    "answer": "understand",
    "answerDetails": "I hope you understand that."
  },
  {
    "id": 3779,
    "question": "correo",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que mi abuela es la única persona que todavía corresponde por correo.",
    "answer": "mail, post, courier",
    "answerDetails": "I think my grandma is the only person who still corresponds via mail."
  },
  {
    "id": 3780,
    "question": "atacar",
    "questionDetails": "Los trabajadores pueden atacar las pérdidas de empleo amenazadas.",
    "answer": "strike",
    "answerDetails": "Workers may strike over threatened job losses."
  },
  {
    "id": 3781,
    "question": "poderoso",
    "questionDetails": "Caminar es un poderoso trabajo en caliente.",
    "answer": "powerful, mighty, potent",
    "answerDetails": "Walking is powerful hot work."
  },
  {
    "id": 3782,
    "question": "casarme",
    "questionDetails": "Encontré alguien para casarme.",
    "answer": "marry, get married",
    "answerDetails": "I found someone to marry."
  },
  {
    "id": 3783,
    "question": "supiste",
    "questionDetails": "Tú siempre supiste que era desechable.",
    "answer": "knew",
    "answerDetails": "You always knew it was disposable."
  },
  {
    "id": 3784,
    "question": "declaraciones",
    "questionDetails": "Gracias por sus declaraciones.",
    "answer": "statements, declarations, depositions",
    "answerDetails": "Thank you for your statements."
  },
  {
    "id": 3785,
    "question": "funcionando",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo lisina buena,y funcionando.",
    "answer": "running, working, functioning",
    "answerDetails": "I got lysine up and running."
  },
  {
    "id": 3786,
    "question": "provecho",
    "questionDetails": "Intenta sacarle provecho a la situación.",
    "answer": "advantage, profit, avail",
    "answerDetails": "Try to take advantage of the situation."
  },
  {
    "id": 3787,
    "question": "aburrida",
    "questionDetails": "Muy aburrida y ordinaria.",
    "answer": "boring, bored, dull",
    "answerDetails": "Very boring and ordinary."
  },
  {
    "id": 3788,
    "question": "mandando",
    "questionDetails": "Esta es base, estamos mandando refuerzos.",
    "answer": "sending, commanding",
    "answerDetails": "This is base, we are sending reinforcements."
  },
  {
    "id": 3789,
    "question": "quitaron",
    "questionDetails": "Me quitaron la mitad del pulmón izquierdo.",
    "answer": "removed",
    "answerDetails": "I removed half of my lung, my left lung."
  },
  {
    "id": 3790,
    "question": "bañar",
    "questionDetails": "Nos vamos a bañar todos juntos.",
    "answer": "bathing, bathe",
    "answerDetails": "We are all bathing together."
  },
  {
    "id": 3791,
    "question": "cumpliendo",
    "questionDetails": "Ese no soy yo cumpliendo mi destino.",
    "answer": "fulfilling, serving, compliance",
    "answerDetails": "This is not me fulfilling my destiny."
  },
  {
    "id": 3792,
    "question": "viuda",
    "questionDetails": "La viuda ha sido notificado.",
    "answer": "widow",
    "answerDetails": "The widow has been notified."
  },
  {
    "id": 3793,
    "question": "tenerla",
    "questionDetails": "Entonces debe tenerla él.",
    "answer": "have",
    "answerDetails": "Then he must have it."
  },
  {
    "id": 3794,
    "question": "miembros",
    "questionDetails": "Nuestros miembros son bastante exclusivos.",
    "answer": "membership",
    "answerDetails": "Our membership is very exclusive."
  },
  {
    "id": 3795,
    "question": "decidiste",
    "questionDetails": "Decidiste no comer hoy?",
    "answer": "decided",
    "answerDetails": "Decided not to eat today?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3796,
    "question": "arroz",
    "questionDetails": "Arroz con leche.",
    "answer": "rice",
    "answerDetails": "Rice pudding."
  },
  {
    "id": 3797,
    "question": "arreglando",
    "questionDetails": "Nosotros nos estabamos arreglando para salir.",
    "answer": "fixing, arranging, mending",
    "answerDetails": "We were just fixing to leave."
  },
  {
    "id": 3798,
    "question": "contestó",
    "questionDetails": "Hablé con una orientadora y contestó todas mis preguntas.",
    "answer": "she answered, she responded",
    "answerDetails": "I talked to a counselor and she answered all my questions."
  },
  {
    "id": 3799,
    "question": "salvaste",
    "questionDetails": "Escuchamos que salvaste el día.",
    "answer": "saved",
    "answerDetails": "We heard you saved the day."
  },
  {
    "id": 3800,
    "question": "sucedido",
    "questionDetails": "Sabemos lo que te ha sucedido.",
    "answer": "happened, succeeded, occurred",
    "answerDetails": "We know what happened to you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3801,
    "question": "desea",
    "questionDetails": "¿Desea aprender cómo tomar control de tu vida?",
    "answer": "do you want",
    "answerDetails": "Do you want to learn how to take control of your life?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3802,
    "question": "oyendo",
    "questionDetails": "Estamos oyendo muchos disparos.",
    "answer": "hearing, listening, listenin’",
    "answerDetails": "We are hearing a barrage of gunfire."
  },
  {
    "id": 3803,
    "question": "obsesión",
    "questionDetails": "Ella se preocupaba por él con una devoción que rodea a la obsesión.",
    "answer": "obsession, preoccupation",
    "answerDetails": "She cared for him with a devotion bordering on obsession."
  },
  {
    "id": 3804,
    "question": "funcione",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo una idea que quizás funcione.",
    "answer": "work, operate, run",
    "answerDetails": "I got an idea that might just work."
  },
  {
    "id": 3805,
    "question": "hablarme",
    "questionDetails": "Sé de alguien que puede hablarme de esto.",
    "answer": "tell me",
    "answerDetails": "I know somebody who can tell me about it."
  },
  {
    "id": 3806,
    "question": "agarro",
    "questionDetails": "Yo agarro el volante.",
    "answer": "grab",
    "answerDetails": "I grab the wheel."
  },
  {
    "id": 3807,
    "question": "diferencias",
    "questionDetails": "El puente entre todas nuestras diferencias.",
    "answer": "differences, dispute, gap",
    "answerDetails": "The bridge between all our differences."
  },
  {
    "id": 3808,
    "question": "correcta",
    "questionDetails": "No es la respuesta correcta.",
    "answer": "correct, right, proper",
    "answerDetails": "No is the correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 3809,
    "question": "creciendo",
    "questionDetails": "Mi negocio está creciendo.",
    "answer": "growing",
    "answerDetails": "My business is growing."
  },
  {
    "id": 3810,
    "question": "responsables",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que todos somos responsables.",
    "answer": "responsible, accountable, liable",
    "answerDetails": "I think we’re all responsible."
  },
  {
    "id": 3811,
    "question": "traerme",
    "answer": "Bring"
  },
  {
    "id": 3812,
    "question": "colega",
    "questionDetails": "Tú colega pasó por aquí buscándote.",
    "answer": "colleague",
    "answerDetails": "Your colleague was here looking for you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3813,
    "question": "círculo",
    "questionDetails": "Sentarse en círculo.",
    "answer": "circle",
    "answerDetails": "To sit in a circle."
  },
  {
    "id": 3814,
    "question": "esperándote",
    "questionDetails": "Me sentía rara esperándote adentro.",
    "answer": "waiting",
    "answerDetails": "I felt funny waiting inside."
  },
  {
    "id": 3815,
    "question": "verdes",
    "answer": "Green"
  },
  {
    "id": 3816,
    "question": "postre",
    "questionDetails": "¿Qué hay de postre?",
    "answer": "pudding",
    "answerDetails": "What’s for pudding?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3817,
    "question": "máxima",
    "questionDetails": "La máxima que las acciones hablan más fuerte que las palabras.",
    "answer": "maxim",
    "answerDetails": "The Maxim that actions speak louder than words."
  },
  {
    "id": 3818,
    "question": "pastilla",
    "questionDetails": "La caja trae 30 pastillas.",
    "answer": "pill, pickup, lozenge",
    "answerDetails": "The box has 30 pills."
  },
  {
    "id": 3819,
    "question": "levanto",
    "answer": "Wake up"
  },
  {
    "id": 3820,
    "question": "beneficio",
    "questionDetails": "Te daré el beneficio de la duda en cuanto a si fue deliberado o no.",
    "answer": "benefit, profit, advantage",
    "answerDetails": "I’ll give you the benefit of the doubt as to whether it was deliberate or not."
  },
  {
    "id": 3821,
    "question": "pleno",
    "questionDetails": "Aunque el Presidente fue elegido democráticamente, su gobierno hizo una transición gradual hacia el poder pleno.",
    "answer": "plenary, middle of",
    "answerDetails": "Though the President was democratically elected, his government gradually shifted toward plenary power."
  },
  {
    "id": 3822,
    "question": "pego",
    "questionDetails": "Él le pego a mi auto.",
    "answer": "hit, paste",
    "answerDetails": "He hit my car!"
  },
  {
    "id": 3823,
    "question": "ponerlo",
    "questionDetails": "Necesitas sacar tu cuchillo y ponerlo en la mesa ahora mismo. Tu padre se pondría como loco si supiera de esto.",
    "answer": "set it",
    "answerDetails": "You need to take out your knife and set it on the table right now. Your father would flip out if he knew about this."
  },
  {
    "id": 3824,
    "question": "bajamos",
    "questionDetails": "Bajamos a dos y medio.",
    "answer": "down",
    "answerDetails": "Down at two and a half."
  },
  {
    "id": 3825,
    "question": "empiezas",
    "questionDetails": "Empiezas por las esquinas.",
    "answer": "start",
    "answerDetails": "Start with the corners."
  },
  {
    "id": 3826,
    "question": "duermo",
    "questionDetails": "Digo mis oraciones y duermo.",
    "answer": "sleep, fall asleep",
    "answerDetails": "I say my prayers and sleep."
  },
  {
    "id": 3827,
    "question": "iniciar",
    "questionDetails": "La semana que viene iniciaremos una nueva etapa en nuestra empresa.",
    "answer": "begin, commence",
    "answerDetails": "Next week, we begin a new phase for our company."
  },
  {
    "id": 3828,
    "question": "saluda",
    "questionDetails": "Saluda a tu hijo de mi parte.",
    "answer": "greets, say hello, say hi",
    "answerDetails": "Greets your son from me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3829,
    "question": "vendo",
    "questionDetails": "Yo vendo suministros para talleres de maquinarias.",
    "answer": "sell",
    "answerDetails": "I sell supplies to machine shops."
  },
  {
    "id": 3830,
    "question": "usan",
    "questionDetails": "Ustedes usan muchos otros nombres.",
    "answer": "use, wear",
    "answerDetails": "You use many other names."
  },
  {
    "id": 3831,
    "question": "actual",
    "questionDetails": "Para mantenerse a una profundidad actual.",
    "answer": "current",
    "answerDetails": "To stay at a current depth."
  },
  {
    "id": 3832,
    "question": "cobra",
    "questionDetails": "No, no es una cobra.",
    "answer": "cobra, charges, cashes",
    "answerDetails": "No it’s not a cobra."
  },
  {
    "id": 3833,
    "question": "gustaban",
    "questionDetails": "Creí que te gustaban los animales.",
    "answer": "liked, wer",
    "answerDetails": "I thought you liked animals."
  },
  {
    "id": 3834,
    "question": "laura",
    "answer": "Laura"
  },
  {
    "id": 3835,
    "question": "francisco",
    "answer": "Francis"
  },
  {
    "id": 3836,
    "question": "padrino",
    "questionDetails": "Él es el padrino de su hijo.",
    "answer": "godfather, sponsor, godparent",
    "answerDetails": "He is godfather to her son."
  },
  {
    "id": 3837,
    "question": "bolas",
    "questionDetails": "Le dio una patada en las bolas.",
    "answer": "balls",
    "answerDetails": "He kicked him in the balls."
  },
  {
    "id": 3838,
    "question": "jugada",
    "questionDetails": "El mariscal de campo calentó el brazo antes de la primera jugada.",
    "answer": "scrimmage",
    "answerDetails": "The quarterback warmed up his arm before the first scrimmage."
  },
  {
    "id": 3839,
    "question": "narices",
    "questionDetails": "Siempre ha tenido olfato para las narices.",
    "answer": "noses, hell, nostrils",
    "answerDetails": "You always did havea nose for noses."
  },
  {
    "id": 3840,
    "question": "aceptó",
    "answer": "she agreed"
  },
  {
    "id": 3841,
    "question": "bruto",
    "questionDetails": "Un peso bruto de despegue proyectado de 500.000 Libras.",
    "answer": "gross, raw, brute",
    "answerDetails": "A projected gross take-off weight of 500,000 pounds."
  },
  {
    "id": 3842,
    "question": "príncipe",
    "questionDetails": "Creemos que la caja del príncipe era el blanco.",
    "answer": "prince",
    "answerDetails": "We believe the prince’s box was the target."
  },
  {
    "id": 3843,
    "question": "persiguiendo",
    "questionDetails": "Estabas persiguiendo al tipo fuera de posición.",
    "answer": "chasing after, chasing, pursuing",
    "answerDetails": "You went chasing after this guy out of position."
  },
  {
    "id": 3844,
    "question": "moviendo",
    "questionDetails": "Esta cosa se está moviendo.",
    "answer": "moving, wagging, shaking",
    "answerDetails": "This thing is moving."
  },
  {
    "id": 3845,
    "question": "despedirme",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo quería pasar y despedirme en persona.",
    "answer": "say goodbye, saying goodbye",
    "answerDetails": "I just wanted to come and say goodbye in person."
  },
  {
    "id": 3846,
    "question": "agradecido",
    "questionDetails": "Estaban agradecidos de que la guerra finalmente terminó.",
    "answer": "thankful, appreciative",
    "answerDetails": "They were thankful that the war was finally over."
  },
  {
    "id": 3847,
    "question": "sospechas",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo que tus sospechas son peores.",
    "answer": "suspicions, suspicious",
    "answerDetails": "Only your suspicions are worse."
  },
  {
    "id": 3848,
    "question": "alerta",
    "questionDetails": "Las fuerzas de seguridad están en alerta para un aumento de la violencia.",
    "answer": "alert",
    "answerDetails": "Security forces are on the alert for an upsurge in violence."
  },
  {
    "id": 3849,
    "question": "tiros",
    "questionDetails": "Algunas personas se agacharon y otras salieron corriendo cuando escucharon los tiros.",
    "answer": "gunfire",
    "answerDetails": "Some people got down and others started running when they heard the gunfire."
  },
  {
    "id": 3850,
    "question": "ábreme",
    "questionDetails": "Ábreme eso, ¿sí?",
    "answer": "open",
    "answerDetails": "Open that for me, will you?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3851,
    "question": "pescado",
    "questionDetails": "Pastelillo de pescado.",
    "answer": "fish",
    "answerDetails": "Fish cake."
  },
  {
    "id": 3852,
    "question": "gallo",
    "questionDetails": "Inclusive olvidé alimentar al gallo antes de venir.",
    "answer": "rooster",
    "answerDetails": "I even forgot to feed the rooster before leaving home."
  },
  {
    "id": 3853,
    "question": "juzgado",
    "questionDetails": "El juez llegó al juzgado para dar inicio a un largo día de procesos judiciales.",
    "answer": "courthouse",
    "answerDetails": "The judge arrived at the courthouse to begin a long day of trials."
  },
  {
    "id": 3854,
    "question": "amiguito",
    "questionDetails": "Hola, amiguito, ¿cómo estás?-Bien.",
    "answer": "little buddy",
    "answerDetails": "Hey, little buddy, how are you?-Good."
  },
  {
    "id": 3855,
    "question": "contestas",
    "questionDetails": "Ya no contestas al teléfono.",
    "answer": "answer",
    "answerDetails": "You no longer answer your phone."
  },
  {
    "id": 3856,
    "question": "discreción",
    "questionDetails": "Todo lo qu pedimos es discreción.",
    "answer": "discretion",
    "answerDetails": "All we ask for is your discretion."
  },
  {
    "id": 3857,
    "question": "colaboración",
    "questionDetails": "El nuevo disco de la cantante es una colaboración con varios artistas famosos.",
    "answer": "collaboration",
    "answerDetails": "The new CD of the singer is a collaboration with several famous artists."
  },
  {
    "id": 3858,
    "question": "atreves",
    "questionDetails": "No te atreves a marchar ni a quedarte.",
    "answer": "dare, presume",
    "answerDetails": "You dare not to leave nor to stay."
  },
  {
    "id": 3859,
    "question": "engañó",
    "questionDetails": "Lo hicimos luego de que engañó a ese mafioso.",
    "answer": "cheated, tricked, deceived",
    "answerDetails": "We put it together after she cheated on that mobster."
  },
  {
    "id": 3860,
    "question": "terminan",
    "questionDetails": "Las huellas terminan en el barranco.",
    "answer": "end, finish",
    "answerDetails": "The footprints end at this gorge."
  },
  {
    "id": 3861,
    "question": "cometió",
    "questionDetails": "Además, usted cometió otro pequeño error.",
    "answer": "committed",
    "answerDetails": "It committed another small mistake."
  },
  {
    "id": 3862,
    "question": "podéis",
    "questionDetails": "También os podéis lavar.",
    "answer": "can",
    "answerDetails": "You can wash at the well."
  },
  {
    "id": 3863,
    "question": "interesar",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo una oportunidad comercial que te puede interesar.",
    "answer": "interest, interesting",
    "answerDetails": "I have a business opportunity that might interest you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3864,
    "question": "calmar",
    "questionDetails": "Un trago de brandy podría calmar sus nervios.",
    "answer": "soothe, defuse",
    "answerDetails": "A shot of Brandy might soothe his nerves."
  },
  {
    "id": 3865,
    "question": "cáncer",
    "questionDetails": "¿Qué porcentaje de la población muere del cáncer de mama?",
    "answer": "cancer",
    "answerDetails": "What percentage of the population dies of breast cancer?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3866,
    "question": "escondidas",
    "questionDetails": "Dices que no están escondidas, pero lo están.",
    "answer": "hidden, sneak, sly",
    "answerDetails": "You say they are not hidden, but they are."
  },
  {
    "id": 3867,
    "question": "abuso",
    "questionDetails": "Protección contra el fraude y el abuso.",
    "answer": "abuse, misuse",
    "answerDetails": "Protection against fraud and abuse."
  },
  {
    "id": 3868,
    "question": "decírtelo",
    "questionDetails": "Estaba a punto de decírtelo.",
    "answer": "say",
    "answerDetails": "I wasjust about to say that."
  },
  {
    "id": 3869,
    "question": "dispuestos",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo hay unos cuantos dispuestos a donar.",
    "answer": "willing, arranged, ready",
    "answerDetails": "There are only so many willing donors."
  },
  {
    "id": 3870,
    "question": "decida",
    "questionDetails": "Decida el formato de nombre para los archivos importados.",
    "answer": "decide",
    "answerDetails": "Decide on the naming format for the imported files."
  },
  {
    "id": 3871,
    "question": "alegre",
    "questionDetails": "La habitación estaba pintada de colores alegres.",
    "answer": "cheerful, joyful, jolly",
    "answerDetails": "The room was painted in cheerful colours."
  },
  {
    "id": 3872,
    "question": "riesgos",
    "questionDetails": "Aun conociendo todos los riesgos, decidimos estar aquí.",
    "answer": "risks, hazards, chances",
    "answerDetails": "We all knew the risks when we signed on."
  },
  {
    "id": 3873,
    "question": "insiste",
    "questionDetails": "La compañía de seguros insiste.",
    "answer": "insists, stresses, adamant",
    "answerDetails": "The insurance company insists."
  },
  {
    "id": 3874,
    "question": "informar",
    "questionDetails": "No te olvides de informar al médico si estás tomando otros medicamentos.",
    "answer": "inform, report, advise",
    "answerDetails": "Remember to inform your doctor if you are taking any other medication."
  },
  {
    "id": 3875,
    "question": "serías",
    "questionDetails": "Me impresionó escuchar que serías voluntario.",
    "answer": "‘d",
    "answerDetails": "I was shocked to hear you’d volunteered."
  },
  {
    "id": 3876,
    "question": "tuvieras",
    "questionDetails": "Él quería que tuvieras esto.",
    "answer": "have",
    "answerDetails": "He wanted you to have that."
  },
  {
    "id": 3877,
    "question": "agradable",
    "questionDetails": "El tiempo es muy agradable en Ixtapa.",
    "answer": "pleasant, enjoyable, friendly",
    "answerDetails": "The weather is very pleasant in Ixtapa."
  },
  {
    "id": 3878,
    "question": "preciso",
    "questionDetails": "Un jugador que puede entregar Pases largos y precisos a los derechistas.",
    "answer": "accurate, necessary",
    "answerDetails": "A player who can deliver long accurate passes to the wingers."
  },
  {
    "id": 3879,
    "question": "sentirse",
    "questionDetails": "Le hago sentirse bien.",
    "answer": "feel",
    "answerDetails": "I make him feel good."
  },
  {
    "id": 3880,
    "question": "periódicos",
    "answer": "some papers"
  },
  {
    "id": 3881,
    "question": "presupuesto",
    "questionDetails": "Mantener dentro del presupuesto del hogar.",
    "answer": "budget, quote, quotation",
    "answerDetails": "Keep within the household budget."
  },
  {
    "id": 3882,
    "question": "fracaso",
    "questionDetails": "Los líderes no pudieron ponerse de acuerdo y la reunión fue un fracaso.",
    "answer": "failure",
    "answerDetails": "The leaders could not agree and the meeting was a failure."
  },
  {
    "id": 3883,
    "question": "tranquilamente",
    "questionDetails": "El bebé está durmiendo tranquilamente en su cuna.",
    "answer": "quietly, calmly, peacefully",
    "answerDetails": "The baby is sleeping quietly in his crib."
  },
  {
    "id": 3884,
    "question": "naranja",
    "questionDetails": "Naranjada F.",
    "answer": "orange",
    "answerDetails": "Orange squash."
  },
  {
    "id": 3885,
    "question": "comió",
    "answer": "Ate"
  },
  {
    "id": 3886,
    "question": "comprando",
    "questionDetails": "Estaba comprando partes para un cohete.",
    "answer": "buying, purchasing, shopping",
    "answerDetails": "I was buying parts for a model rocket."
  },
  {
    "id": 3887,
    "question": "sabor",
    "questionDetails": "No me gusta el sabor de las uvas verdes.",
    "answer": "taste, flavor, flavour",
    "answerDetails": "I don’t like the taste of green grapes."
  },
  {
    "id": 3888,
    "question": "principios",
    "questionDetails": "Y gente sin principios, mejor todavía.",
    "answer": "principles, early, beginning",
    "answerDetails": "And people without principles, even better."
  },
  {
    "id": 3889,
    "question": "dilo",
    "questionDetails": "Dilo cinco veces rápido.",
    "answer": "say",
    "answerDetails": "Say that five times, fast."
  },
  {
    "id": 3890,
    "question": "sabría",
    "questionDetails": "Pero allí nadie sabría quiénes somos.",
    "answer": "know",
    "answerDetails": "But nobody will know who we are."
  },
  {
    "id": 3891,
    "question": "sintió",
    "questionDetails": "Usted sintió la necesidad de revelar esta sesión.",
    "answer": "felt, sensed",
    "answerDetails": "You felt the need to reveal this session."
  },
  {
    "id": 3892,
    "question": "veníamos",
    "questionDetails": "Tenemos lo que veníamos a buscar.",
    "answer": "came",
    "answerDetails": "We got what we came for."
  },
  {
    "id": 3893,
    "question": "normalmente",
    "questionDetails": "Normalmente, tarda 3 o 4 años en completar el entrenamiento.",
    "answer": "normally, usually",
    "answerDetails": "Normally, it takes three or four years to complete the training."
  },
  {
    "id": 3894,
    "question": "miembro",
    "questionDetails": "Mi hermano acaba de ser nombrado miembro honorífico del nuevo instituto de investigaciones.",
    "answer": "fellow",
    "answerDetails": "My brother was just named as an honorary fellow at the new research institute."
  },
  {
    "id": 3895,
    "question": "escribiendo",
    "questionDetails": "Me paso medio día escribiendo.",
    "answer": "writing, typing",
    "answerDetails": "I spend half my day writing."
  },
  {
    "id": 3896,
    "question": "físico",
    "answer": "physique"
  },
  {
    "id": 3897,
    "question": "pintar",
    "questionDetails": "Volando detrás de las colinas disminuye la capacidad del enemigo para pintar con radar.",
    "answer": "paint",
    "answerDetails": "Flying Behind Hills lessens the enemy’s ability to paint you with radar."
  },
  {
    "id": 3898,
    "question": "enteren",
    "questionDetails": "Probablemente no se enteren de nada hasta mañana.",
    "answer": "know",
    "answerDetails": "They probably won’t know anything about this news until tomorrow."
  },
  {
    "id": 3899,
    "question": "llamarte",
    "questionDetails": "Intentaré llamarte mañana.",
    "answer": "call you",
    "answerDetails": "I’ll try to call you tomorrow."
  },
  {
    "id": 3900,
    "question": "lluvia",
    "questionDetails": "Nube de lluvia, nubarrón M.",
    "answer": "rain",
    "answerDetails": "Rain cloud."
  },
  {
    "id": 3901,
    "question": "trabajó",
    "questionDetails": "Mi papá trabajó para él.",
    "answer": "worked, labored",
    "answerDetails": "My dad worked for him."
  },
  {
    "id": 3902,
    "question": "hablarlo",
    "questionDetails": "Podemos hablarlo con ellos.",
    "answer": "talk",
    "answerDetails": "We can talk to them about this."
  },
  {
    "id": 3903,
    "question": "violento",
    "questionDetails": "Tiene fama de ser violento. No lo fastidiaría.",
    "answer": "violent",
    "answerDetails": "He’s known for being violent. I wouldn’t anger him."
  },
  {
    "id": 3904,
    "question": "resistencia",
    "questionDetails": "Oponer or ofrecer resistencia.",
    "answer": "resistance, strength, stamina",
    "answerDetails": "To put up or offer resistance."
  },
  {
    "id": 3905,
    "question": "avanzar",
    "questionDetails": "Es casi imposible avanzar por la ciudad en esta lluvia torrencial.",
    "answer": "progress, proceed",
    "answerDetails": "It is almost impossible to progress through town in this driving rain."
  },
  {
    "id": 3906,
    "question": "paró",
    "questionDetails": "Mi compañero paró para ayudar a una dama en peligro.",
    "answer": "stopped, quit",
    "answerDetails": "My partner stopped to help a damsel in distress."
  },
  {
    "id": 3907,
    "question": "volvía",
    "questionDetails": "Mientras alguien volvía a mi vida alguien más se iba.",
    "answer": "returned",
    "answerDetails": "As someone returned to my life someone left."
  },
  {
    "id": 3908,
    "question": "alberto",
    "answer": "Alberto"
  },
  {
    "id": 3909,
    "question": "carmen",
    "answer": "Carmen"
  },
  {
    "id": 3910,
    "question": "cabrones",
    "questionDetails": "Esos cabrones me lo robaron.",
    "answer": "bastards, fuckers, motherfuckers",
    "answerDetails": "Those bastards stole it from me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3911,
    "question": "ángeles",
    "questionDetails": "Pero no había bebés ni ángeles.",
    "answer": "angels, la",
    "answerDetails": "But there weren’t any babies or any angels."
  },
  {
    "id": 3912,
    "question": "tantito",
    "answer": "little bit"
  },
  {
    "id": 3913,
    "question": "cálmese",
    "questionDetails": "Su majestad, cálmese.",
    "answer": "calm down",
    "answerDetails": "Your majesty, calm down."
  },
  {
    "id": 3914,
    "question": "coca",
    "questionDetails": "Chris fue encarcelado por vender coca a estudiantes.",
    "answer": "coke",
    "answerDetails": "Chris went to jail for selling Coke to students."
  },
  {
    "id": 3915,
    "question": "parís",
    "answer": "Paris"
  },
  {
    "id": 3916,
    "question": "enojado",
    "questionDetails": "¿por qué estás enojado conmigo?",
    "answer": "angry",
    "answerDetails": "Why are you angry with me?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3917,
    "question": "advierto",
    "questionDetails": "Le advierto que no me toque.",
    "answer": "warn",
    "answerDetails": "I warn you not to touch me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3918,
    "question": "mas",
    "questionDetails": "Mas a tu izquierda.",
    "answer": "more, most, plus",
    "answerDetails": "More to your left."
  },
  {
    "id": 3919,
    "question": "disparó",
    "questionDetails": "Vi quien me disparó.",
    "answer": "shot, fired, shooter",
    "answerDetails": "I saw who shot me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3920,
    "question": "casita",
    "questionDetails": "Vivo en una casita en un pueblo que se enclava en las montañas.",
    "answer": "little house",
    "answerDetails": "I live in a little house in a town that is nestled in the mountains."
  },
  {
    "id": 3921,
    "question": "arriesgar",
    "questionDetails": "¿De veras arriesgarías este puesto por el que has trabajado tan duro involucrándote en un escándalo así?",
    "answer": "hazard, jeopardize",
    "answerDetails": "Would you really hazard this job you’ve worked so hard for by getting involved in a scandal like that?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3922,
    "question": "amores",
    "questionDetails": "Sus manos, rostros, sus amores y temores.",
    "answer": "loves, sweethearts, amours",
    "answerDetails": "Their hands, faces, their loves and fears."
  },
  {
    "id": 3923,
    "question": "piscina",
    "questionDetails": "Nadamos en la piscina todos los sábados.",
    "answer": "pool",
    "answerDetails": "We swim at the pool every Saturday."
  },
  {
    "id": 3924,
    "question": "balas",
    "questionDetails": "Las balas entran en los cañones.",
    "answer": "bullets, bales, slugs",
    "answerDetails": "The bullets go into the barrels."
  },
  {
    "id": 3925,
    "question": "institución",
    "answer": "establishment"
  },
  {
    "id": 3926,
    "question": "preocupar",
    "questionDetails": "Se van a preocupar si no.",
    "answer": "worry",
    "answerDetails": "Are going to worry if not."
  },
  {
    "id": 3927,
    "question": "cementerio",
    "questionDetails": "Tatiana no quería vivir en una casa al lado de un cementerio porque le daba escalofríos.",
    "answer": "graveyard",
    "answerDetails": "Tatiana didn’t want to live in a house right next to a graveyard because it gave her the creeps."
  },
  {
    "id": 3928,
    "question": "mandamos",
    "questionDetails": "Quieres dinero, y nosotros te lo mandamos.",
    "answer": "send",
    "answerDetails": "You want money and we send it."
  },
  {
    "id": 3929,
    "question": "queréis",
    "questionDetails": "Bueno, supongo que queréis la verdad.",
    "answer": "want, ye",
    "answerDetails": "I suppose you want the truth."
  },
  {
    "id": 3930,
    "question": "unidad",
    "questionDetails": "Juan recibió un premio por vender el mayor número de unidades este año fiscal.",
    "answer": "unit",
    "answerDetails": "Juan received a prize for selling the most units this fiscal year."
  },
  {
    "id": 3931,
    "question": "creyendo",
    "questionDetails": "Déjalos seguir creyendo eso.",
    "answer": "believing, fancying, thinking",
    "answerDetails": "Let them go on believing it."
  },
  {
    "id": 3932,
    "question": "ofreciendo",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo estaba ofreciendo reparar el techo.",
    "answer": "offering, providing, featuring",
    "answerDetails": "I was just offering to fix this roof here."
  },
  {
    "id": 3933,
    "question": "empresario",
    "questionDetails": "El empresario como demandado dispone de la …",
    "answer": "employer",
    "answerDetails": "The employer as defendant has the …"
  },
  {
    "id": 3934,
    "question": "fuentes",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero fabricante, fecha y posibles fuentes.",
    "answer": "sources, fonts, fountains",
    "answerDetails": "I want the maker, date, possible sources."
  },
  {
    "id": 3935,
    "question": "aparecido",
    "questionDetails": "Ha aparecido una moneda caida del cielo.",
    "answer": "appeared, popped up, surfaced",
    "answerDetails": "A fallen currency has appeared of the one sky."
  },
  {
    "id": 3936,
    "question": "pedazos",
    "questionDetails": "Y otros dos pedazos de esta increíble tarta.",
    "answer": "pieces, chunks, bits",
    "answerDetails": "And two more pieces of this incredible pie."
  },
  {
    "id": 3937,
    "question": "arruinar",
    "questionDetails": "No quiero quiero arruinar tu actuación.",
    "answer": "spoil",
    "answerDetails": "Not want to spoil your performance."
  },
  {
    "id": 3938,
    "question": "recibí",
    "questionDetails": "Recibí una carta de mi hijo hoy.",
    "answer": "i received",
    "answerDetails": "I received a letter from my son today."
  },
  {
    "id": 3939,
    "question": "discutiendo",
    "questionDetails": "Necesitamos saber lo que estaban discutiendo.",
    "answer": "discussing, arguing, quarrelling",
    "answerDetails": "We need to know what they were discussing."
  },
  {
    "id": 3940,
    "question": "comportamiento",
    "questionDetails": "El comportamiento de Jimmy mejoraba cuando su papá estaba en casa.",
    "answer": "behavior, behaviour, performance",
    "answerDetails": "Jimmy’s behavior improved when his father was home."
  },
  {
    "id": 3941,
    "question": "echas",
    "questionDetails": "Sé que le echas de menos.",
    "answer": "miss",
    "answerDetails": "I know you miss him."
  },
  {
    "id": 3942,
    "question": "acusado",
    "questionDetails": "El acusado fue ordenado a ser juzgado por una serie de cargos.",
    "answer": "accused",
    "answerDetails": "The accused was ordered to stand trial on a number of charges."
  },
  {
    "id": 3943,
    "question": "acabando",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo seríamos dos personas acabando una conversación.",
    "answer": "finishing, ending, busting",
    "answerDetails": "All we’d be is two people finishing a conversation."
  },
  {
    "id": 3944,
    "question": "borrar",
    "questionDetails": "Voy a borrar todas las fotos de mi computadora porque ocupan demasiado espacio.",
    "answer": "delete, wipe",
    "answerDetails": "I’m going to delete all the photos from my computer because they take up too much space."
  },
  {
    "id": 3945,
    "question": "inocentes",
    "questionDetails": "Ayuda a salvar vidas inocentes.",
    "answer": "innocent",
    "answerDetails": "Helps save innocent lives."
  },
  {
    "id": 3946,
    "question": "rutina",
    "questionDetails": "Diseñamos vacaciones para gente que busca romper con la Rutina.",
    "answer": "routine, rut",
    "answerDetails": "We tailor vacations for people looking for a break from routine."
  },
  {
    "id": 3947,
    "question": "expliqué",
    "questionDetails": "Ya te expliqué que fue por agotamiento.",
    "answer": "explained",
    "answerDetails": "I explained it was for exhaustion."
  },
  {
    "id": 3948,
    "question": "llora",
    "answer": "Cries"
  },
  {
    "id": 3949,
    "question": "pagas",
    "questionDetails": "Si rompes las reglas, lo pagas.",
    "answer": "pay, paychecks",
    "answerDetails": "You break the rules, you pay."
  },
  {
    "id": 3950,
    "question": "tíos",
    "questionDetails": "¿Quiénes son Antonio y Marcos?-Son mis tíos por parte de madre.",
    "answer": "uncles",
    "answerDetails": "Who are Antonio and Marcos?-They’re my uncles on my mom’s side."
  },
  {
    "id": 3951,
    "question": "formal",
    "questionDetails": "Necesitamos una declaración formal.",
    "answer": "formal, formally",
    "answerDetails": "We need a formal statement."
  },
  {
    "id": 3952,
    "question": "objeto",
    "questionDetails": "El Instituto se abrió con el objeto de promover el estudio científico.",
    "answer": "object, subject, purpose",
    "answerDetails": "The Institute was opened with the object of promoting scientific study."
  },
  {
    "id": 3953,
    "question": "inconsciente",
    "questionDetails": "“¿Qué es?”, dijo de nuevo, inconsciente de la repetición.",
    "answer": "unconscious",
    "answerDetails": "‘What is it?’ he said again, unconscious of the repetition."
  },
  {
    "id": 3954,
    "question": "quiten",
    "questionDetails": "Quiten esta mochila de aquí.",
    "answer": "remove",
    "answerDetails": "Remove the bag from here."
  },
  {
    "id": 3955,
    "question": "sonríe",
    "questionDetails": "La cara de Paula se ilumina cuando sonríe.",
    "answer": "she smiles",
    "answerDetails": "Paula’s face lights up when she smiles."
  },
  {
    "id": 3956,
    "question": "dudar",
    "questionDetails": "Nunca debo dudar de mí mismo.",
    "answer": "doubt",
    "answerDetails": "I should never doubt myself."
  },
  {
    "id": 3957,
    "question": "llevarse",
    "answer": "get away with"
  },
  {
    "id": 3958,
    "question": "letras",
    "questionDetails": "El erudito era un hombre de letras.",
    "answer": "letters, lettering",
    "answerDetails": "The scholar was a man of letters."
  },
  {
    "id": 3959,
    "question": "caos",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando se apagaron las luces en el instituto correccional, estalló el caos.",
    "answer": "mayhem",
    "answerDetails": "When the lights went out in the correctional institute, mayhem broke out."
  },
  {
    "id": 3960,
    "question": "botón",
    "questionDetails": "El botón del brillo está al costado.",
    "answer": "control, button",
    "answerDetails": "The brightness control is on the side."
  },
  {
    "id": 3961,
    "question": "llevarle",
    "answer": "take him"
  },
  {
    "id": 3962,
    "question": "fines",
    "answer": "finnish"
  },
  {
    "id": 3963,
    "question": "tomaron",
    "questionDetails": "Tomaron sus libros y se mudaron a otra mesa.",
    "answer": "they took, they drank",
    "answerDetails": "They took their books and moved to another table."
  },
  {
    "id": 3964,
    "question": "elementos",
    "questionDetails": "De los 4 elementos el fuego es el que más me llama la atención.",
    "answer": "elements",
    "answerDetails": "Of the fours elements, fire is the one I relate to most."
  },
  {
    "id": 3965,
    "question": "mueren",
    "questionDetails": "Los que mueren con violencia permanecen.",
    "answer": "die",
    "answerDetails": "Those who die violently remain tortured."
  },
  {
    "id": 3966,
    "question": "alternativa",
    "questionDetails": "La otra alternativa está aquí.",
    "answer": "alternative",
    "answerDetails": "The second alternative is here."
  },
  {
    "id": 3967,
    "question": "fechas",
    "questionDetails": "Ya tiene todos los nombres y fechas en su cabeza.",
    "answer": "dates",
    "answerDetails": "All the names and dates are inside your head."
  },
  {
    "id": 3968,
    "question": "física",
    "questionDetails": "Porque es la ley de la física.",
    "answer": "physics",
    "answerDetails": "Because it’s the law of physics."
  },
  {
    "id": 3969,
    "question": "repartir",
    "questionDetails": "Baraja las cartas antes de repartirlas.",
    "answer": "deal",
    "answerDetails": "Shuffle the cards before dealing."
  },
  {
    "id": 3970,
    "question": "llegará",
    "questionDetails": "Sin mí, el proyecto no llegará a ninguna parte.",
    "answer": "will",
    "answerDetails": "Without me, the project will go nowhere."
  },
  {
    "id": 3971,
    "question": "clásico",
    "questionDetails": "Hiciste el error clásico de las películas.",
    "answer": "classic",
    "answerDetails": "You made the classic movie mistake."
  },
  {
    "id": 3972,
    "question": "contaba",
    "questionDetails": "Lo que contaba era la interpretación dramática.",
    "answer": "counted, reckoned, had",
    "answerDetails": "It was more a dramatic interpretation that counted."
  },
  {
    "id": 3973,
    "question": "pensábamos",
    "questionDetails": "Los dos pensábamos que se había acabado todo.",
    "answer": "thought",
    "answerDetails": "We both thought it was all over."
  },
  {
    "id": 3974,
    "question": "iremos",
    "questionDetails": "Y ahora iremos a dar un paseo tranquilo.",
    "answer": "we ‘re going",
    "answerDetails": "And now we’re going to take a nice quiet walk."
  },
  {
    "id": 3975,
    "question": "sufre",
    "questionDetails": "Todo lobo sufre sus pulgas.",
    "answer": "suffers, undergoes, sufferer",
    "answerDetails": "Every wolf suffers fleas."
  },
  {
    "id": 3976,
    "question": "daban",
    "questionDetails": "Ellos simplemente te daban cosas.",
    "answer": "gave",
    "answerDetails": "They just gave you things."
  },
  {
    "id": 3977,
    "question": "apunta",
    "questionDetails": "Le apunta con cuidado.",
    "answer": "aims, points, targets",
    "answerDetails": "He aims real careful."
  },
  {
    "id": 3978,
    "question": "hágame",
    "questionDetails": "Y hágame saber cómo van las cosas en el reino.",
    "answer": "let me",
    "answerDetails": "And let me know how things go in the kingdom."
  },
  {
    "id": 3979,
    "question": "muñeca",
    "questionDetails": "Le regalaron una muñeca por su cumpleaños.",
    "answer": "doll",
    "answerDetails": "She got a doll for her birthday."
  },
  {
    "id": 3980,
    "question": "ramón",
    "questionDetails": "Ramón asiste a la escuela de la esquina.",
    "answer": "raymond",
    "answerDetails": "Raymond attends the school on the corner."
  },
  {
    "id": 3981,
    "question": "secuestro",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando se llevó al bebé equivocado de la guardería, fue acusado de secuestro.",
    "answer": "kidnapping, abduction, hijacking",
    "answerDetails": "When he took the wrong baby from the nursery, he was charged with kidnapping."
  },
  {
    "id": 3982,
    "question": "políticos",
    "questionDetails": "Espero que nosotros como políticos también lo estemos.",
    "answer": "politicians, political",
    "answerDetails": "I hope that we as politicians are too."
  },
  {
    "id": 3983,
    "question": "producción",
    "questionDetails": "La producción de ciertas hormonas bajo estrés.",
    "answer": "output, yield, production",
    "answerDetails": "The output of certain hormones under stress."
  },
  {
    "id": 3984,
    "question": "empresas",
    "questionDetails": "Las empresas serias nunca las garantizan ni prometen.",
    "answer": "companies, enterprises, businesses",
    "answerDetails": "Legitimate companies never guarantee or promise scholarships."
  },
  {
    "id": 3985,
    "question": "cuidadito",
    "answer": "Cuidadito"
  },
  {
    "id": 3986,
    "question": "auxilio",
    "questionDetails": "El salvavidas acudió en su auxilio cuando se cayó en el océano.",
    "answer": "aid",
    "answerDetails": "The lifejacket came to his aid when he fell into the ocean."
  },
  {
    "id": 3987,
    "question": "actriz",
    "questionDetails": "Mi hermana es una actriz famosa.",
    "answer": "actor",
    "answerDetails": "My sister is a well-known actor."
  },
  {
    "id": 3988,
    "question": "afortunadamente",
    "questionDetails": "Afortunadamente, no se dispararon disparos y nadie resultó herido.",
    "answer": "fortunately, happily",
    "answerDetails": "Fortunately, no shots were fired and no one was hurt."
  },
  {
    "id": 3989,
    "question": "confíe",
    "questionDetails": "Confíe en algunos o en todos nuestros servicios integrados …",
    "answer": "rely, trust, confide",
    "answerDetails": "Rely on a few, or all of our integrated services …"
  },
  {
    "id": 3990,
    "question": "deudas",
    "questionDetails": "Son deudas que nunca se pagan.",
    "answer": "debts, dues, bills",
    "answerDetails": "These are debts that can never be repaid."
  },
  {
    "id": 3991,
    "question": "hueco",
    "questionDetails": "Vincent esconde efectivo en un hueco en la pared detrás del sofá.",
    "answer": "hollow, hole, recess",
    "answerDetails": "Vincent hides cash in a hollow in the wall behind the sofa."
  },
  {
    "id": 3992,
    "question": "avisarle",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo que avisarle al mundo.",
    "answer": "warn, notify, tell",
    "answerDetails": "I have to warn the world."
  },
  {
    "id": 3993,
    "question": "informado",
    "questionDetails": "Ella es muy bien informado sobre el ganado y pedigres.",
    "answer": "knowledgeable",
    "answerDetails": "She is very knowledgeable about livestock and pedigrees."
  },
  {
    "id": 3994,
    "question": "explícame",
    "questionDetails": "Explícame porque ni siquiera hablas de eso.",
    "answer": "explain",
    "answerDetails": "Explain because neither even talk about that."
  },
  {
    "id": 3995,
    "question": "dueños",
    "questionDetails": "Espero que los dueños estén fuera.",
    "answer": "owners, property owners, masters",
    "answerDetails": "Hope the owners are out."
  },
  {
    "id": 3996,
    "question": "armó",
    "questionDetails": "Y también lo armó con una cota de malla.",
    "answer": "armed",
    "answerDetails": "Also he armed him with a coat of mail."
  },
  {
    "id": 3997,
    "question": "perdono",
    "questionDetails": "También te perdono por eso.",
    "answer": "forgive, pardon",
    "answerDetails": "I forgive you for that, too."
  },
  {
    "id": 3998,
    "question": "putos",
    "questionDetails": "Mírame a los putos ojos.",
    "answer": "fucking, fuckers, faggots",
    "answerDetails": "Look at my fucking eyes."
  },
  {
    "id": 3999,
    "question": "favores",
    "questionDetails": "Mientras ella se desvestía, Elliot se preguntaba cómo habría tenido la suerte de que esta belleza le otorgara sus favores.",
    "answer": "favors",
    "answerDetails": "As she disrobed, Elliot wondered how he had been fortunate enough to have this beauty bestow her favors upon him."
  },
  {
    "id": 4000,
    "question": "cueste",
    "questionDetails": "De veras espero que esto no nos cueste la competencia.",
    "answer": "cost",
    "answerDetails": "I really hope that this doesn’t cost us the competition."
  }
]
